《变形金刚4：绝迹重生》
哦 倒霉 达茜 你真是不应该来
Oh, shit. Darcy, you really shouldn't have come.
那可未必
Show me.
(北极)
公司要我们继续运做
Corporate was adamant. We keep running.
所有工作都不能停
No stopping operations.
不不不 你也要过安检 不可以带相机
No, no, no. You got to go through. No cameras.
他的子弹可不长眼
He's got orders to kill.
国际法在这不管用
I don't even think international laws apply up here.
我们的身份首先是地质学家
We are geologists first.
只要这个东西一旦具有重大的历史意义
If this thing has any historical significance at all,
我们就得停止运作 我要亲自让它停止
we are shutting down. I'm shutting us down.
别开枪
No!
他想开枪 那来吧
Oh, he's going to shoot me? Shoot me.
嘿 你还真想杀死她啊
Hey, don't kill her.
这家伙简直是疯了
This is crazy stuff.
这东西真邪门
Crazy shit.
我说 你怎么看
Well, what do you think?
我觉得历史将要被改写了
I think history is about to change.
(美国 德州)
(铭记芝加哥事件 通报外星人活动)
(伊格研发中心)
∮ 我是个无情的女人 ∮
∮ I'm a nasty woman ∮
有人终于要来上班了
Oh, look who decided to show up for work.
∮ 我总是令人心碎 ∮
∮ I'm a heartbreaker ∮
∮ 能够让你痛哭 ∮
∮ Gonna make you cry ∮
天气预报说海边不适合冲浪了
What, surf report no good at South Padre?
浪头不够高 车子又没油了
The waves are flat and I got no gas.
你懂的 凯德
You know that, Cade.
哥们 真不礼貌
Dude. Rude.
哦 看看这两小妞 真性感
Look at these two junebugs.
喔 小心肝
Whoo! My, my!
凯德 这次你会付我工钱吧
Hey, you're paying me on this one, right, Cade?
拜托 给我吃颗定心丸
Please tell me I'm getting paid.
卢卡斯 有工作做你就知足吧
You know, Lucas, a lot of guys are just happy to have a job at all.
也是哈
Yeah, I suppose.
身上有现金吗
You got any cash on you?
有呀
Yeah.
太好了
All right, good.
嘿 我是卢卡斯·法兰纳瑞
Hey, Lucas Flannery.
我们家从1928年就掌管这个地方
Place has been in the family since '28.
我爷爷他一辈子都扒在这儿了
Granddaddy ran it all his life. Ain't that right, Granddaddy?
不过 这很快就会转到我的名下
Real soon he's going to sign it over to me.
还不都是现在这电影给害的
The movies nowadays, that's the trouble.
不是拍续集就是重拍 造了一堆垃圾
Sequels and remakes, bunch of crap.
那部电影我很喜欢
I love that one. Oh.
他老了 听不见了
He's deaf and senile.
我听见了
Heard that.
这些机器稍微修整 就可以放数字电影
Now these just need some spit and polish. I believe they're digital,
连IMAX都可能
Possibly IMAX.
可能才怪
Yeah, they're not.
让我们自己来吧 我们看着办
Mister, we'll have a look around if you want to leave us to it, okay?
以前呢 大家都会千里迢迢
You know, folks used to come from miles around
来这里看舞女跳恰恰舞
to see the dancing girls with the big cha-chas.
我真想趁他换尿布的时候给他麦片里下毒
I swear to God, I am one diaper change away from poisoning his oatmeal.
嘿 没事你就来转转
Hey, you hang in there, buddy.
如果能在这重温青春
If coming here makes you feel young,
你就让他天天带你来
Then you tell this kid to bring you here every day.
想让我闭嘴 就卖七块
Seven bucks, I keep talking.
成交
Sold.
你还记得这个地方吗
Remember this place when we were kids?
高中时候你带几个姑娘来过
How many girls you think you brought here in high school?
我只记得一个
I only remember one.
嘿 小心头
Hey, heads!
难怪你选不上校队呢
That's why you didn't make the varsity team.
好吧 看我的长传
All right. Go long.
别管那球了
Leave it.
迫击炮弹壳 你都经历些什么呀
Mortar shells? What the hell happened to you?
嘿 小伙子
Hey, snakeballs.
这卡车多少钱
How much for the truck?
卡车
Truck?
咱们再扛两个星期 所有的课就全都上完了
Two more weeks, girls, till no more classes, ever.
到时候一定要晒成古铜色再喝个烂醉
Almost time to get a tan and get wasted!
(已修物品放置处 费用随意)
(伊格机器人)
拜托了 拜托了
Please, please.
(申请被拒绝)
没有助学金 太棒了
No financial aid. Great.
行了 我知道我到家了 谢谢你
Yes, I know I'm home, thank you.
发现闯入者 严禁私闯民宅
Intruder alert! Back away from the premises!
好好识别声音 是我
Voice recognition. It's me!
我要打电话报警了
I am dialing 911.
随你的便 我无所谓
Go right ahead. I don't care.
我要打电话报警了
I'm still calling 911.
芝加哥之战从此改变了世界
The Battle of Chicago was an event that permanently changed our world.
死亡人数超过1300人
Over 1,300 dead.
大片市区惨遭摧毁
Much of the city has been destroyed.
国土安全部号召所有人
Homeland Security is urging everyone
举报可疑的外星人活动
to report suspicious alien activity.
国会迅速反应
A swift act of Congress,
中止了美军与汽车人的
Put an end to all joint operations,
所有联合作战行动
Between the military and the Autobots,
这个联盟关系就此终止
Ending the alliance.
各位委员都知道
As this committee knows,
五年前入侵芝加哥事件
The Invasion of Chicago was a defining day,
是我们国家命运的转折点
For our nation five years ago.
数百万人在那天意识到
The day millions of people realized that,
我们不能再允许外星人
never again can we allow aliens,
把我们卷入宇宙战争了
To fight our battles for us.
在联合作战行动废除之后
A handful of Autobots were given sanctuary,
那几个汽车人获得了安置
after joint-combat operations were abolished.
只剰下十来个霸天虎还在四处逃窜
Fewer than a dozen Decepticons are still on the run.
这多亏我们中情局的
Thanks to our CIA unit,
墓风小队
"Cemetery Wind."
至于外星人的科技
As for the alien technology,
我们的目标是让美国将其彻底掌控
our objective remains to keep it in American control.
嗨 我叫提摩西 这是我的小组
Hi. My name is Timothy. This is my crew.
我们在芝加哥发现了外星的旋转炮塔
We found this alien ball turret in Chicago.
这部是在瓦砾堆发现的 而且竟然还能用
We just found it in the rubble and it's all working...
有传言说日本 印度和以色列
Word has it Japan, India, the Israelis,
可能持有若干艘机器人飞船
May have gotten their hands on a couple of ships.
俄罗斯正开高价收购
Apparently the Russians are starting a bidding war.
只要五千美元我们就卖
We're taking $5,000 for it.
这有三十六支枪 全部都是外星装备
It's got 36 guns, alien shit.
新时代已经开启
A new era has begun.
而変形金刚时代
And the age of the Transformers,
已经结束了
is over.
嘿
Hey.
Hey,
我等你好久了
I've been waiting for you.
你今天真漂亮
You're looking hot today!
哦 是吗 要不你把上衣脱了吧
Oh, yeah? How about you take your shirt off?
你要我现在脱掉上衣
You want me to take my shirt off right now?
万一被你爸看到怎么办
What would your dad think of that?
嘿 你去哪儿
Hey, where you going?
真不敢相信 太夸张了
I cannot believe him. I cannot believe this.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
往前开
All the way!
一辆卡车
A truck?
爸 你该不会把钱都砸在这卡车上了吧
Dad, please tell me you didn't spend our money on this.
别担心 他花的是我的钱
Oh, no, don't worry, he didn't. He spent my money.
一共一百五十美元
A hundred and fifty bucks of it.
那就当是你工资的预付款吧
As an advance on your regular paycheck.
我什么时候有工资了
What regular paycheck?
工资会发给你的
Which you will get back.
- 什么时候 - 没戏了 我们破产了
- When? - Never. We're broke.
果不其然
I knew it.
宝贝
Sweetheart,
你能不能别挑拨老板和雇员的关系好吗
Could you please not drive a wedge between employer and employee.
咱俩不是是合伙人关系吗
Hold on. I thought we were partners.
听着 我手头紧 好吧
Look, I came up short, okay?
我要给她买毕业舞会的礼服
I had to buy her a prom dress.
你难道不让我买吗
You want me to deny her a prom dress?
不买也行 反正你不让她约会
You might as well. You denied her a prom date.
怎么会 我只是要陪她去跳舞
No, I offered to take her and chaperone.
谁想和自己老爸跳舞啊 搞笑
Nobody wants to go to the dance with their dad. It's weird.
这根本就不是个问题
It's not the issue.
或许这就是个问题
Well, maybe it should be.
你们能不能别拿我说什么
Hey, could you guys Just get Off my case?
你知道这引擎值多少钱
You know what the engine on this runs for?
我可以把它拆了卖掉
I can break it down and strip it for parts.
宝贝 我总觉得你的裤子越来越缩水
And sweetheart, your shorts are shrinking by the second, okay?
应该先冷水洗再烘干 拜托
Cold water, air dry, please.
她身材真火辣
I think she looks hot.
你说什么
What did you say?
就像我个单纯的小姑娘
Like a hot teenager.
哦 单纯小姑娘 这说法还算恰当 谢谢
Oh, it's the "teenager" thing that makes it better. Thank you.
我可不是这个意思
It didn't sound like what it meant.
去拿个接线板来
That goes by the circuit boards.
东西就放那边吧
Put the Zeiss lenses over there.
爸 拜托 别再花钱
Dad, please. You can't keep spending money on junk,
把一堆废品变成另一堆废品了
just so you can turn it into different junk.
这些怎么能说是废品呢
We do not use the "J" word in here.
这古董放映机可是稀有的很
That is a Super Simplex theater projector. It's very rare.
还有"微笑领肮员" 怎么样
What about the SmilePilot?
还有这"除草运动机"都是划时代的发明
Or the Exer-Mower that I invented? Simply ahead of their time.
就跟那只没用的机器看门狗一样
Yeah, like the alleged Guard-Dawg.
你看你惹它生气了
You're gonna get him upset.
嘿 凯德 凯德
Hey, Cade! Cade!
这玩意儿还能用吗
This thing still work?
- 不能 - 当然能用
- No! - Yes.
这都是领先的科技
Yes, and still groundbreaking.
你可以找一把躺椅坐下来等它送冰睥酒
Go back there and lay on the recliner and just wait for a cold one.
别再搞破坏了 伙计
Dude, stop breaking stuff.
催缴单和滞纳通知单
Final notice, late notice, past due.
过来过来 给老爸把酒拿来 快点
Come on, come on. Bring Daddy the alcohol. Come on.
哎呀你这都是从哪收的破烂儿啊
I mean, what is all this crap people send you?
那是CD随身听和老式磁带 听音乐用的
That's a Discman and that's an 8-track tape. Music.
从来没听说过
Never heard of it.
修好这个可以卖一百块
Look, I fix that, it's 100 bucks.
那个卖二百五十块
I fix that, it's $250.
那个如果没被你摔坏
If I would have been able to fix that before you broke it even more,
还可以卖二十块
It would have been 20 bucks.
这些钱再加上奖学金
This stuff is what's gonna put you through college,
完全能供你上大学了
As long as you land one of those scholarships.
像它这样伺候一趟平均要花多长时间
What's the estimated time of arrival, usually? Average?
等等 它只会把酒拿到你附近
Wait. So it just brings the beer near you?
这就算完了
That's the trick?
- 一两个小瑕疵别在意 - 好吧
- It's got a couple kinks, man. - Yeah.
爸 有些东西根本就不该被发明出来
Dad, you think maybe some things should never be invented?
不 你错了 这是落伍的想法
No, I don't. That's backwards thinking.
这里是科技的殿堂 一个神圣的地方
This is a temple of technology. You guys are standing in a holy place.
你们觉得怎么样啊 看看这地方多宽敞
What do you think? Why don't you look at all of this?
全都是你的 这景色多棒
This could be yours. What about this land?
那个母夜叉又来了 兴致还挺高
Purple People Eater's back and she looks hungry.
这房子很棒是不是
Isn't this incredible?
嘿 嘿 说你呢 这房子是我的 我不卖
Hey, Hey. you! I own this house! It's not for sale!
伊格先生 你已经六个月没还房贷了
Six months late on payments, Mr. Yeager.
你还从电线杆子上偷电用
And I see you stealing power at the pole.
那也不关你的事
Hey, that's not your concern.
先生 你想参观一下吗
Sir, do you wanna see the property?
当然
Sure.
我很乐意先带你们去看
I'd be more than happy to give you a tour.
其他买家的下场
I'll show you three other buyers I got buried out back,
然后再用这根球棍打爆你们的头
Then I'll crack your head open like an egg!
- 哦 天哪 - 退后 他疯了
- Whoa! Whoa! - Stay back! He's crazy.
前几日告诉过不要再来了 可你又来干什么
I told you don't come back here anymore.
再敢过来我就要报警
I will have my brother come back and beat your ass!
你等着有你好瞧的
Don't you start with me.
让我哥来收拾你 他可不是吃素的
And I'll bring the police when I come, too! My brother ain't no joke!
谁 杰瑞
Who, Jerry?
你瞧他那个肥样
You bring his big ass up here,
上个车会把车都给挤翻了
He's gonna be huffing and puffing before he can squeeze out of that car!
你给我听着
You back out on my grass,
你再胆敢把车开进来你就死定了
You're gonna be in big trouble!
让杰瑞那小子来找我呀
You tell Jerry to come see me.
我打的他满地找牙
I'll give him some pecan pie.
她竟敢撞坏我的离芭墙
She smashed through the fence?
凯德 放松点 你都快气的心梗了
Cade, relax. You're going to have an aortic infarction.
什么意思
What is that?
意思就是心脑血管病
I think it's a brain heart attack.
那我已经病过一会了
Yeah, I've had one already.
我们现在还偷电用啊
So we're stealing power now?
哪里 只是跟邻居们借一下
No, we're borrowing it from the neighbors.
行啊 真有你的
Great. That's awesome.
等我毕业离开家以后 谁来照顾你呢
Once I graduate and I'm gone, who's gonna take care of you?
哦 你照顾我
Oh, you take care of me?
那又是谁教你焊接的
Who taught you how to solder a circuit?
是谁教你编程 梳小辫
Or write a program? Or French braid your hair?
玩橄榄球的都是我 我照顾你
Or throw a spiral? Me. That's what I do.
某人做菜只会用番茄酱
Who taught you how to cook without ketchup,
而且根本不会理财
Or balance your checkbook?
到底是谁在扮演大人的角色
Who always has to be the grownup around here?
好吧 你有理 行吧
All right, you got a point, okay?
但这也说明我们配合默契
But that means we're a great team.
我知道最近家里状况不太好
And I know it's been sucky around here lately.
但是会好起来的
But we're gonna be fine, sweetie.
你要有信心 好吗
You just gotta keep believing, okay?
大发明家都是这样 我保证有一天
I mean, that's what great inventors do. I promise you, one day,
我一定会弄出大发明来的
I'm gonna build something that matters.
我相信你 爸爸
I believe you, Dad.
你妈妈会以你为荣的
You know, your mom would be very proud of you.
一切都会好的
It's going to be okay.
散开 向右推进
Spread out! Push right!
快点 快点 快点
Roll, roll, roll, roll.
给我两个人 给我两个人
Give me two. Give me two.
上沙滩 慢慢来
Take the beach, nice and easy.
好的 保持现有位置
All right, hold what you got.
启动迷你肮拍机
Release the mini-drones.
(墓风小队)
航拍机已升空 航拍机已升空
The mini-drones was on, The mini-drones was on,
直升机 老鹰已接近 准备开火
Vipers. Eagle in sight. Cleared hot.
探测到热源了
Got a heat sig.
最靠近船首的第二根烟囱
Second stack. Closest to the bow.
掠食者-01 瞄准目标区域
Predator 0-1. Captured target area.
准备弹药 全员进入
Set charges.
报告长官 我是枪手01
Leader, leader, this is Gunfighter 0-1.
老鹰正在进入内部第二层
Eagles moving internal. Second deck.
到左舷
Take the port
蛙人83 蛙人83
Frogman 83, Frogman 83.
向左方推进
To the left push
已进入最上层
Breached site on rooftop.
告诉其他部门待命
Have Echo Platoon on standby.
告诉直升机我们要出来了
Let the helo know we're moving external!
收到 收到
I got! I got!
A小队负责左眩 B小队负责右舷
Alpha, take port. Bravo, take starboard.
往右 往右
Shift right. Shift right.
快快 快快
Go! Go!...
将烟囱炸开
Cracking steel!
不
No!
快 开火
Hit him!...
立即开火
Fire.
导弹发射 危险目标靠近
Missiles out. Danger close.
他要逃 快上
He's running! Move!
他要逃走 他要逃走 跟着目标
He's on the run! He's on the run!
不 拜托了
No! Please!
别开火
Hold your fire.
别开火啦
Hold! Hold fire!
你们没看到我受伤了吗
Can you not see? I've been injured.
不许动 不许动
Box him in. Box him in.
我是医务官救护车
Medical Officer Ratchet!
我是你们的盟友
I'm a friend!
我是汽车人
I'm an Autobot!
那你为什么要逃
Then why are you running?
我收到预警信息 是擎天柱发的
Optimus sent this distress message.
呼叫所有汽车人
Calling all Autobots.
我们被列为攻击目标了
We are under targeted attack.
停止与人类的任何联系
Cease all contact with humans.
我们都躲了起来
We're all hiding.
所有汽车人都在被追杀
All Autobots are being hunted.
我们深处危险之中
We're all in danger.
芝加哥之战 我失去了妹妹
I lost a sister in Chicago.
体想我同情你
You'll get no sympathy from me.
你们人类出了什么毛病啊
What's wrong with you humans?
不 求求你们
No! Please.
停火 别开枪 都别开枪
Check fire, check fire!
现在我来了结他
He's mine now.
禁闭
Lockdown.
汽车人和霸天虎就像小屁孩一祥
Autobots, Decepticons. Like little children,
没完没了的打闹
Always fighting.
闹的整个宇宙都不得安宁
Making a mess out of the universe.
最后还得由我来收拾烂摊子
Then I've got to clean it up.
要想活命就必须告诉我 他藏在哪儿
There is one way you survive. Tell me where he's hiding.
擎天柱到底在哪儿
Where is Optimus Prime?
休想
Never.
那我现在就成全你
Never is here.
我得说中情局自你接手行动工作以来
I must say, it is remarkable, really astounding,
表现得相当出彩 令人眼前一亮
The success that the CIA has had since you have taken operational control,
而且是这样 总统要我来问问你
And so the President has asked me to ask you
另外也问问他
To ask him,
是否愿意接受邀请来白宫坐一坐
To invite you both over to the White House just to powwow,
就是介绍情况 更多的讲讲细节
where we get maybe some more specifics
跟我们说一说你们是如何
About how exactly,
追杀霸天虎残余旧部的
You're hunting the enemy Decepticons left.
我当局长才两年
I've had my desk for two years.
艾汀杰先生已经干了二十五年了
Mr. Attinger has been here for 25.
他负责的案子 我从来不过问具体细节
He runs the projects where I don't ask for specifics.
那都是"暗地里"的行动
That's why they're called Black Ops.
正因为如此我们晩上才睡的安稳
And why we all sleep better at night.
明白了 好极了 那么...
Check. That is great. So, um...
有什么爆料吗 你们进展的怎么样
Any dirt on that? Uh, how, uh, that's going?
成果斐然
Outstanding.
好 太好了
Great. Oh, great.
这正是我想要的 总统会很欣慰的
I was hoping to hear that. The President will be pleased.
因为 虽然我是这个星期一
'Cause, I'll tell you right now,
才当上幕僚长的
I've only been Chief of Staff since Monday, um,
但是我很清楚 只有谈到外星人大战
But I do know that the alien war stuff, these are...
这种会面才会有意思
These are the only fun meetings.
我的职责并非取悦总统
Look, I'm not here to entertain the President,
但你可以告诉他
But you may tell him,
战争就要结束了
That the war will be over.
快了
Soon.
要是万一他问起这事
"...be over..." In case he asks,
我会转达你的原话 战争就快结束了
I just like to have an exact quote. "War will be over soon."
这个太棒了 多好的消息
That is great. Such good news.
对了 还有 嗯...
And, um,
我想总统先生
The President would,
以为对他的了解
I know, just love...
一定会非常乐意 非常非常乐意
Really, really love to press the flesh...
和汽车人领袖握个手之类的或者是拍张合影
Not flesh, obviously, but just maybe get a shot with, um...
你们怎么称呼他 擎天柱勋爵还是爵士
Is it Lord Prime? Sir Prime?
我们要不就在空军一号上面会面吧
We could bop on Air Force One.
大家拥抱一下合个影
It'd be just a quick bop, then we just bop in and bop back.
估计是不可能了
I wouldn't get his hopes up on that one.
而且 他就叫擎天柱
He's called Optimus Prime.
是外星武装人员
Alien combatant.
而且是非法的
Here illegally.
他们不是盟友吗 这是怎么回事
But aren't they our friends? Why?
因为他们只要还在地球上
Because our world will never truly be safe,
世界就不会太平
Till all of them are gone.
哦 好吧 那要不这样
Oh. Well, I would hope,
我还可以办一个类似道别仪式之类的活动
We could do a much more ceremonial farewell.
好歹我们的军队还和他们并肩战斗过
Especially since our military has worked so closely with them.
有你吗
Until you.
地球不是他们的 从来都不是
It's not their planet. Never was.
该夺回主导权了
Time we take it back.
好的 再来
All right, come on. Come on.
太好了 太好了 对
Yes. Yes. Yes.
哦 就是这祥 不 坚持住
Oh, there you go. No, hold it.
你别抖啊 你抖什么啊
Stop shaking! Why are you shaking?
我又不会解雇你
You have the job!
你忘了吃晩餐
You forgot to eat dinner!
知道我为什么担心你了吧
You see why I worry?
对不起宝贝 我...
Look, sorry, sweetie, I...
我差点就成功了
I almost got it working right.
跟您说个事
So, listen,
我已经做完功课 期末考也考完了
I'm done with homework and set with finals,
我想和朋友开车出去玩
so I was just gonna take a little drive with some friends
这个可以吗
if that was okay with you.
不许带男生 这个我知道 等毕了业再说
No boys, I know. Graduate first.
没错
Exactly.
可别人家都没有这种规矩
You do know no one else has this rule, right?
规矩
Rule?
别说的这么难听好吗 这叫智慧
Don't make it sound harsh, okay. It's wisdom.
大晩上了 就别开车出去了
I don't think we need to be driving around in the middle of the night.
七点四十五 天都快黑了
It's already like quarter to eight. It's almost dark.
斯巴德 你消停一会好吗
Spud, will you stop it?
知道我毕业的时候在干什么
You know where I was for my graduation?
知道 我的出生就是个错误
Yes. With me, the mistake.
是个惊喜 孩子
The surprise, Tess.
是我人生中最美的事
And the best thing that ever happened.
我们看起来不开心吗
Do we look unhappy? Huh?
那是我人生中最棒的一天
No. It's the greatest day of my life.
你妈妈去世之前我答应过她
I made your mother a promise before she passed.
我们的宝贝女儿不能错过毕业典礼
Our baby's gonna be at her graduation. That's it.
男生高中的时候都是懵懵懂懂的
High school boys know nothing.
之后才能成熟
It's only later they turn into men.
所以你当初要是成熟就不会有我了
So if you were older and wiser, I wouldn't exist.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
现在咱们俩都不谈恋爱
You know, this is a non-dating household, okay?
你不谈我也不谈 这样可以吗
You don't date, I don't date. That's it.
或许你该恋爱了
Well, maybe you should.
泰莎 等等
Tessa, wait.
泰莎
Tessa?
Look.
我知道我管的太多了 但不这样不行啊
I know I've been on you, okay? But I have to be.
十二岁到十七岁的青春期是公认的风险期
Twelve to seventeen is the official teenage danger window.
而我的职责就是帮你顺利的度过
It's my job to get you through it.
你生气我也得管
So you can be pissed off all you want.
好吧 好 那...
And, yes, you can...
你就跟朋友出去玩吧
Take a ride with your friends.
好的
Okay.
干活别熬夜
Don't work all night.
记得吃饭
And eat.
她是最美的礼物 艾米莉
Best thing that ever happened, Emily.
有了她是我人生中最棒的事
She's the best thing that ever happened.
你一定会自豪的
You'd be proud.
哦 不
Oh, no.
万万没有想到
Unbelievable.
万万没有想到 见鬼
Unbelievable. God!
真该把这些东西卖了补贴家用
Something in here needs to make this family some money.
那就从你开始吧 老家伙
Come on, you old wreck. Judgment Day.
他人呢
Where is he?
不知道
I don't know.
(驱逐通知)
发现闯入者 发现闯入者
Intruder alert! Intruder alert!
你个没用的破烂
Asshole.
现在拨通报警电话
I am dialing 911.
泰莎 我也算是你的叔叔
Tess, I'm basically your uncle.
你的家就是我的家
Su casa es mi casa.
而咱们家就要保不住了
And we're going to lose the casa.
爸
Dad!
来啦
Coming!
你在测试激光吗
Are you working with lasers?
要是的话我就不进来了
If so, I'm not coming in.
我从来没见过这种卡车
You guys have never seen a truck like this before.
快进来 把门锁上
Get in here. Lock that door.
这破门哪有锁
It doesn't have a lock.
你看
Look!
它的散热器上的洞 瞧这个尺寸
Look at the hole in the radiator. Look at the size of it.
有东西能把它打个洞
Something blew a hole in it!
那又怎么样
Yeah, so?
这车身不是一般的钢铁
It's not normal steel.
引擎里的弹片 把线路都切断了
The shrapnel in the engine, it ripped all the connections apart.
看好了 我的天才马上就用上了
And watch. And this took some Cade genius.
你们一定会喜欢这个的
You are gonna love this.
当我重新接上蓄电池
When I hook this back to a working battery...
呼叫所有的
Calling all...
呼叫所有的汽车人
Calling all Autobots.
没错 他根本就不是卡车
Oh, yeah. I don't think it's a truck at all.
我们找到了变形金刚
I think we just found a Transformer.
变形 呃 快撤
Tran... Ugh! Evacuate!
等等 你们
Wait! Guys!
爸 我说你是不是疯了
Dad, are you out of your mind?
你必须把那东西弄走
You need to get that thing out of here.
这不用担心
You don't have to worry.
我整晩都在里面工作 沒问题
I've been in there working all night. I'm fine.
什么没问题 那不是卡车好吗
You know what? That's not a truck, okay? You're right.
那是外星杀人机器 我的天哪
It's an alien killing machine. Jesus.
老兄 他早死了 早就坏了
Dude. It's DOA. It's been recalled, totaled, done.
听我说 我知道个热线电话
So, listen, there's a number that you call.
你应该拨打这个号码告诉美国政府
You're supposed to call the government.
这是作为美国公民应该做的
It's the American thing to do.
你还来劲了
Here we go.
你应该马上就打 如果真是外星人的话
You're supposed to call, and if it ends up being alien,
你可以赢得两万五千美元的奖励
then you win $25,000.
这不是赢钱的事
You don't win money.
还有要是能活捉它
And if you can capture it live...
并贴上野生动物的标签
Like tag it like a wild wildebeest,
你就能赢得十万美元
Then you get $100,000.
- 爸爸 快打电话 - 我听说的
- Dad, we're making the call. - I heard that.
我看过那个广告 他们没有说有奖金
I've seen the commercial. They don't say that.
- 现在就打电话 - 你是说他们在骗人
- That's not a guarantee. - You think Greg would lie to me?
如果他真的是芝加哥的変形金刚的话
Look, if that's a Transformer there from the Battle of Chicago,
我要知道他的来由
I need to know how it works.
我是个发明家 搞不好就会一夜成名
I'm an inventor. This could be a game changer for me!
如果它的技术能用在我的发明上
If I can apply that technology to my inventions,
我们就再也不用为钱发愁了
we'd never have to worry about money again.
这种话我可听腻了
I've heard that before.
两万五付大学学费和房贷全都够了
Twenty-five grand! It pays for my college. It pays for the house.
再说了 这卡车是花我的钱买来的吧
Besides, you used my money to buy the truck, right?
所以准确的说 这卡车是我的
So technically, that's my truck.
你说呢
Don't you think?
你可是签过有关研究室知识产权的合约的
You also signed a contract regarding all research lab I.P.
什么研究室 这不是个库仓吗
Research lab? It's a barn, dude.
你签过合约 现在又来反对我
You signed it and now you're competing.
你的所有点子都属于我
Any idea of yours is mine.
所有的想法也属于我 你的人都属于我
Any thought you have, I own it, so basically, I own you.
我怎么不觉得你可以拥有谁
I don't think you can own someone.
那都是很久以前的事了 都是老黄历了
That was, like, a while ago, even in Texas.
行了 把焊枪拿过来帮我弄一下吊臂
All right. Bring the torch over and help me with the pulley arm.
弹片摧毁了它的电力核心
I think the shrapnel took out its power core.
哦 泰莎 你看这个
Oh, and, Tessa, you see this?
我的天啊
Oh, shit.
外星杀人机器会允许我这么做吗
Would an alien killing machine let me do that?
听着 我会报告政府会拿到钱的
Look, I'll make the call. We'll get the money.
但先让我研究一番
Just first let me see if I'm right.
你想躲在家里就回去吧
You want to hide in the house? Go ahead.
好吧
Okay.
行了 动手吧
Let's go. Pulley arm.
我真不敢相信他
I can't believe him!
那是什么玩意儿
What is that?
看起来来像导弹
Looks like a missile.
就是
It is! Whoa!
爸
Dad!
有颗导弹 就在客厅里
There's a missile in the family room!
啊 不会吧
Holy...
我要杀了你
I'll kill you!
不 不
No! No!
爸 有颗导弹在...
Dad, there's a missile in...
我要杀了你们 给我退后 退后
I'll kill you! Stay back!
别开火 别开火
Oh, no. Don't shoot. Don't shoot!
快 打 911
Call 911! Run!
- 卢卡斯 - 别跑
- Lucas! - Stop!
你别乱动 冷静一下
Lucas? Don't move, just calm down.
给我悠着点 人类
Easy, human.
你别动 他不会伤害我们的
Stay there. He's not going to hurt us.
我的武器系统损坏了
Weapons systems damaged.
一颗导弹击中了你的引擎
A missile hit your engine.
我们把他拿了出来
And we took it out of you.
你伤的相当重
You're hurt really bad.
我只是想帮助你
I'm just trying to help you.
这里是我家 我是工程师 我叫凯德·伊格
You're in my home now. I'm an engineer. My name is Cade Yeager.
凯德 我欠你一个人情
Cade, I am in your debt.
我的名字叫擎天柱
My name is Optimus Prime.
我的汽车人
My Autobots.
他们有危险
They're in danger.
我现在就得走 得离开
I need to go. I need to go now.
你这样怎么能走远呢
How far you think you're gonna get?
泰莎过来 他需要帮助
Tessa, come here. He needs our help.
你这是怎么回事
What happened to you?
人类设计了一个陷阱 突袭了我们
An ambush. A trap. Set by humans.
我逃走 并化身成这样
I escaped and took this form.
可你是我们的盟友
But you're on our side.
那些人为什么要伤害你
Why would humans hurt you?
他们背后另有势力指使
They were not alone.
我的汽车人伙伴 能够把我修好
My Autobots can repair me.
是啊 但是得先找到他们
Yeah. If you can reach 'em.
要不 我来修
What about me?
我警告你地球人 艾汀杰先生
I warn you, Mr. Attinger of Earth,
同盟是一种契约
Alliance is a contract,
而契约和人类如出一辙
And contracts, like humans,
都会到期失效
Expire.
我们地球上有句谚语
On this planet, we have a saying.
敌人的敌人就是朋友
"The enemy of my enemy is my friend."
我也有句口头禅
I also have a saying.
关我屁事
"I don't care."
在墨西哥城发生了什么事
So what happened in Mexico City?
我以为你杀了他们
I thought you had him.
我击中他三次 有一处是致命的
Three direct hits. A mortal wound.
但你的人让他逃脱了
Then your men allowed him to escape.
你答应过要提供他的情报
You promised me human intelligence.
难道你们根本弄不到情报
Or is there such a thing?
你还没告诉我
You know, you've still never told me.
你为什么抓他 你到底听谁的
Why do you want him? Who are you working for?
不管在哪个星系
Every galaxy I've traveled,
你们这个物种都是一个德行
All you species are the same.
你们都觉得你们自己是宇宙的中心
You all think you're the center of the universe.
真是太无知了
You have no idea.
你去趟五金店 把单子上的东西买齐
Go to the hardware store and you get the list. The whole list.
你是想把他修好吗
What, you're going to try and fix him?
他又不是玩具火车好吗
He's not a model train set, Cade.
对 所以他才重要
No, that's right. He's important.
你在乎 可别人呢
Yeah, but important to who?
你不能老把外星人藏在谷仓里呀
You can't keep an alien locked up in your barn.
你想怎么着 把他当玩具呀
What are you gonna do, play with him?
你冷静点
Will you calm down?
冷静个屁 是我被十英尺长的炮打中了
I'm trying to, but I just got hit in the head with a ten-foot cannon!
但愿他吃了你 那辆老爷车就归我了
If he eats you, I get the GTO.
消息绝对不能走漏听见没有
Not a word to anybody. Do you hear me?
一个字都别提 跟谁都别说
Not a single word. Nobody.
(中央情报局)
我们锁定了一个目标
I think we have a lock on a high-value target.
特战小组已经做好了准备
Special Operations group is ready.
有什么进展
What do you got?
长官 特战小组接到来自德州的通报
Sir, Special Ops just got a call from Paris, Texas.
这和离开墨西哥城的卡车是同一辆
Hard match on the truck seen leaving Mexico City.
这个狗娘养的 拿下它
Son of a bitch. Let's go get him.
你遭到了重击
Took a hell of a hit, you know.
导弹和你的电源擦肩而过
The missile just missed your power source.
这叫火种源
We call it a Spark.
他包含我们的生命力
It contains our life force,
同时也有我们的记忆
And our memories.
相当于人的灵魂
Yeah, we call it a soul.
墓风小队出动
Scramble Cemetery Wind.
女生们先生们 都辛苦了
Thank you for your efforts, ladies and gentlemen.
走的时候把灯关上
This room is going dark.
出口在你们左手
The exit is on your left.
我接管这里
I'll take it from here.
好吧 我们走
Okay, let's go.
墓风小组在移动中 重复 在移动中
I'm with Cemetery Wind. We're on the move. Repeat, on the move.
凯德
Cade.
你为什么愿意帮助我
Why are you willing to help me?
因为你也愿意信我
I guess maybe because you trust me to.
我回来了
I'm back!
怎么去了这么久啊
Took you long enough!
因为我半路上去看了趟医生
My head hurts. I had to go to the doctor.
我脑袋肿了
I got a welt on my head,
肿得就像星际迷航里那个反一号
That makes me look like a fricking Star Trek character.
随你怎么讲
Whatever.
看 看啊
Look! Look!
我们进入目标区域
We're on property.
蝰蛇-15正在飞越
Viper 15 overhead. Angels 1.
爸
Dad!
伊格先生 我是詹姆斯·萨沃 联邦探员
Mr. Yeager, my name's James Savoy. I'm a federal agent.
我们正在找一辆废弃的卡车
My men and I are trying to track down an abandoned truck.
你这片地真不错
It's a nice spread you got here.
卖掉的话很可惜
Too bad she's for sale.
谢了 但我不卖
Well, thanks. She's not.
你在找那辆车吗
That the truck you mean?
恐怕不是
Afraid not.
有人打电活报告说
You know, Mr. Yeager, we received a call from someone,
这俩卡车令他忧虑
Concerned about this truck.
哦 我去
Oh, no.
不是你说的吗
That wasn't you?
我的忧虑是你们未经允许
Only thing I'm concerned about is you being on my property,
就闯入我家
Without permission.
跟我们德州人做对是沒有好下场的
You know, we got a rule about people messing with people from Texas.
我也不知道你说的什么卡车
And I don't know what truck you're talking about.
他会夺走美国人的性命
The kind that cost American lives.
进屋给我搜
Search the property!
你们凭什么搜 你们有搜查令吗
What do you mean, "Search the property"? You don't have a warrant.
我这张脸 就是搜查令
My face is my warrant.
等等 你们找到卡车了会给我们奖金是吧
Wait. But if you guys do find a truck, we get a reward, right?
蝰蛇-15盯住A据点
Viper 15 holding, point alpha.
C组 预备
Charlie team, hold tight.
封锁区域
Lock it down.
打开打开快 到左边去
Open, open, open.
呼叫 呼叫 没有异状
Short wall. Short wall.
五号进入
Five in. Five in.
发现闯入者 严禁擅自闯入私宅
Intruder alert! Back away from the premises.
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell is that?
就是个愚蠢的小发明
Just some dumb inventor.
没有问题 没有异常
Clear. Clear.
没有异常 没问题
Clear right. Clear.
注意了 全方位搜索
360. 720. Heads on a swivel.
我们走吧 这里什么也没有
Let's go. There's nothing here.
沒有任何迹象和收获
There's no signs. We got nothing.
长官 垃圾桶里发现未引爆弹头
Sir, we have a live armed missile in the trash.
未引爆
Live?
那是我放进去的你告诉我那是哑弹 凯德
I carried that to the trash! You told me that was a dud, dude.
差点被炸死 对吗
I could be dead. Right?
听我说 我是找到一辆卡车来着
Look. Okay, yes, I found a truck, all right.
我本想拆了卖了 昨晚还在这
I towed it back for the parts. I left it here last night.
可今天早晨他就不见了
This morning, it's gone. When? Where?
我真不知道他去哪儿了 我就知道这么多
I don't know. I swear to God. That's as much as I know about him.
"他"
"Him."
他说了"他" 他知道他在哪儿
He said, "Him." He knows who the son of a bitch is.
伊格先生
Mr. Yeager.
干嘛
What?
恕我冒昧
Excuse me.
你刚才说了"他"
You just said, "Him."
- 把他们拿下 - 什么
- Take them down. - What?
放开我
Ow! Let me go!
他们什么都不知道 问我 快放开我女儿
They don't know about the truck! I know! Just let her go.
什么样的人宁愿背叛亲人
What kind of a man betrays his flesh-and-blood,
也要保护外星人呢
Brethren for alien metal?
把这家伙给我带走
Get this guy out of my sight.
抓她 我女儿不知道卡车的事
Let her go! They don't know about the truck.
好了 上车 搜索整个区域
All right! Load up! Search the perimeter!
卢卡斯 告密的电话是你打的吧
Lucas, you called, didn't you?
不是我 我怎么会认识这些可怕的家伙
No! I don't know any of these scary guys.
你不能对女人动粗 你
Oh, God! You're manhandling a woman!
我饶不了你
I'll kick your ass!
放开她
Let her go!
爸
Daddy!
放开我 爸
Let me go! Daddy!
不 你们不能把我带走 我是美国公民
No! You're not taking me anywhere! I'm an American!
别乱叫 宝贝
Easy, sweetheart.
好 好 好的 好的 好的 是我错了
Okay, okay, okay. All right. Okay. All right. I was wrong.
萨沃
Savoy.
控制那个女孩
Use the girl.
我的天啊
Oh, my God! Ahh!
现在我限你十秒钟说出那辆车
Now, you got ten seconds. Where's the truck?
你们敢对我女儿开枪
You're gonna shoot my little girl?
那是你逼的
If I have to.
求求你别开枪 求求你
Please don't shoot me! Please!
现在我该说的都说了
Look, I don't know. I told you everything that I know!
他不见了走了 之前还在 我敢发誓
He's gone. He left. He was in the barn, I swear to God!
快放开我女儿
Just let her go!
求求你
Please, please.
本来还在的 放开她
He was in there! Let her go!
你还剩七秒
Seven seconds.
我真的没骗你 他本来在的
I'm telling you the truth! He was in there!
爸
Dad!
告诉他 放开我女儿
Tell him to get away from my little girl now!
爸爸
Dad!
谁敢碰我的女儿我就杀了你
You touch her and I'll kill you!
- 该死 - 还剩下两秒了
- God! - You got two seconds.
我要他说真话
I need the truth.
求求你
Please.
毙了她
Shoot her.
我就在这里
Here I am!
趴下
Get down!
凯德 他们打算杀了你们
Cade! They're going to kill you!
快离开这儿
Get out of here!
向右移动 到那边去
Push right! Headed to the house!
快上车快点 大家快走 快点
Come on. Hurry up! Get in the car! Let's go!
老爸 快上车
Daddy, get in the car!
呼叫外围 擎天柱要突围了
Perimeter, Optimus moving your way!
怎么回事宝贝 他们是谁
What's happening, baby? Who are they?
他们要卡车 他们要那辆卡车
It's the truck. They want the truck!
他们是什么人
"Who are they"?
你又是谁啊 凭什么叫他宝贝啊
Who are you, and who are you calling "baby"?
我知道你听见了 回答我的问题
I know you heard me.
- 我是她男朋友 - 他是我男朋友
- I'm her boyfriend! - He's my boyfriend!
什么 你哪来的男朋友
What? You're not her boyfriend!
他叫肖恩 是个车手 老爸
His name's Shane and he drives, Dad.
那都是什么车啊 太吓人了吧
What kind of cars are those? They're so scary!
又有一辆追上来了
There's another one coming up the back!
开到玉米地里甩掉他们
You gotta try to lose them in the cornfield!
他就要追上来了 快
He's coming up behind us! Go!
蝰蛇-15燃料快用尽了
Viper 15, running on fumes. RTB.
我们被困住了
They've got us cornered!
小心 小心 小心
Watch out, watch out, watch out!
伊格先生 我没想在这种情况下跟您见面
Mr. Yeager, this is not how I wanted us to meet, okay?
我叫肖恩 我本来...
I'm Shane, and I'm a completely...
我就没打算跟你说话 好好开你的车
And I am not talking to you! Drive the car!
小心 小心
Watch out! Watch out!
对他们开枪示警
Throw 'em some warning shots!
我沒想到我现在都可以开的这么好
Man, I don't know how I'm driving this good.
又上到一个全新的境界了
It's like, today I've gone to a whole other level.
专心开车 少废话
Road, focus! Stop talking!
肖恩 小心
Shane, look out!
我承认全都是我错了 好吗
This may be primarily my fault, okay.
他们说好会带支票过来
They said they were gonna bring a check!
结果却是特种部队
I didn't know they were gonna send a death squad!
坐稳了
Hang on!
我们当中产生了一位赢家 他就是...
Hey, we got ourselves a winner! Don's got it over here.
当心
Look out!
甩开他们了
We lost them!
干得漂亮 玉米地里的小帅哥
Good job, stranger from the cornfields!
那些吓人的车又追过来了
The scary cars are back.
开到工厂甩掉他们
Lose them at the factory, Shane!
我以为你很会开车的 快
I thought you knew how to drive this thing! Go!
我觉得那钱拿不到了 别惦记了
I don't think we're gonna get that money. Doesn't seem like it.
凯德
Cade!
引他们上楼
Take 'em upstairs!
上五楼甩掉他们
We're losing them on the fifth floor.
用那招 肖恩
Do that thing, Shane!
- 没问题 - 什么 什么招
- You know it. - What do you mean? What thing?
反正这招一使出来 相当的刺激
What we're about to do is gonna be kind of scary.
听看 别让他们跑了 击毙他们
Take out your guns and shoot them!
他们开枪了
They're shooting at us!
- 泰莎 做好准备 帮我拉着 - 什么
- Tessa, grab my stick! Grab my stick! - What?
她的技术是一流的
She's got the best hands in the business.
准备好了吗 走
Ready, Tess? Pull!
不 不 不
No! No! No!
不要往上飞啊
No f-ing way!
噢 耶
Oh! Yeah!
泰莎 看我回去怎么收拾你
Tessa, you are so grounded!
糟了 轮毂裂了
Shit! The rim's cracked.
是擎天柱 快 快下车 走啊
Optimus. Come on, move! Move!
我的脚卡住了 等一下 凯德
My foot's stuck! Wait, Cade!
卢卡斯
Lucas!
等等 等等我
Wait! Wait!
卢卡斯 卢卡斯 小心你上面
Lucas! Lucas, above you!
快跑
Run!
上车 我们快走
Come on, get in, let's go!
你一定很想看看我的表情
I'll bet you wish you could see my face right now.
卢卡斯离开我们了
Lucas, we just left him?
他不在了
He's gone.
对于你们失去朋友一事我表示深切的同情
My deepest sympathies for the loss of your friend.
在我确定沒人跟来之前 呆在这儿
Stay here till I'm sure we weren't followed.
我们现在全都成了目标
We are all targets now.
我们只能到处逃窜了吗
So we're hiding out now? That's the plan?
还得听这位卡车师傅的
We're taking orders from a truck?
你还有什么更好的办法吗
Well, you got a better idea?
嘿 你离他远点 臭小子
Hey, move away from her, kid. Don't...
手放错地方了
Keep your hands off her. All right? No.
你被一个德州的民间发明家弄得灰头土脸
You got your ass kicked by a garage inventor from Texas.
我会给你的档案记上一笔
That goes on your resume.
沒错 你们也都一样
Yeah, it goes on all of yours, too!
你以为我想听你在这发牢骚吗
Do I look like I'm in the mood for any of your shit today?
华盛顿以为我们在追杀霸天虎
Washington thinks we were chasing a Decepticon target,
不先把这一家人拿下来 我们可就露馅了
but our story falls apart if we don't find this Yeager family first.
他如果报警或者找联邦调查局呢
Yeah, well, what if he goes to the cops or the FBI?
他们会转给我们的
They know to hand him over.
他想重回过去是不可能了
His world as he knows it is gone.
往好处想 你们起码认识了
Well, bright side, you guys met.
他是哪的人
Where is he from?
我说了 是德州人 开车的
I told you, he's a driver from Texas.
德州哪儿的
Texas?
难道是德州都柏林市的
Where, Dublin, Texas? Shamrock, Texas?
他那爱尔兰口音真像个妖精
So why does he sound like a leprechaun'?
你在爱尔兰这样说的话 是会挨揍的
You'd get your ass kicked in Ireland for saying that.
但这里是德州 我的小家伙
Well, we're not in Ireland, Lucky Charms. We're in Texas.
你说他是开车的什么意思 职业司机吗
And so he drives? What do you mean, he drives? Like, for a living?
是啊 他起码是靠这个吃饭的
Yeah. At least he makes a living.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看 我是玩赛车的 我是赛车手
Look, I race rally cars. One driver.
再加上个导航员 就是她
One navigator. Her.
对了 这是我的合法工作
By the way, I'm totally legit.
我刚刚被红牛车队相中
I just got picked up by Red Bull.
而且我还要告诉你
And just so you know,
我口袋里的最后一分钱都砸在那辆车上了
my life savings was in that car back there.
你俩不可能成的
This is not happening.
不 这必然是能成的
Oh, it definitely is.
你多大了
How old are you?
二十了
Twenty.
她才是个十七岁的女孩啊
She's a 17-year-old girl.
我给你两条路走
So we can work this two ways.
要么我把你的脸打开花 然后你报警抓我
One, I punch you right in the mouth and you call the police on me.
- 爸 - 或者
- Dad. - Or two,
我报警抓你 因为你违法了 她是未成年人
I just call the cops on you because this is illegal. She's a minor.
不 我们受《罗密欧与茱丽叶法案》保护
We're protected by the Romeo and Juliet laws.
我们交往一阵子了
We dated for a little while.
当时我高二他高四 没事的
I was a sophomore, and he was a senior. It's fine.
怎么可能没事
No, it's not fine.
我们俩交往是合法的
We've got a preexisting,
只不过是早了一点点
Juvenile foundational relationship.
根据2705-3号法律
Statute 22.011.
什么
What?
德州会有这种法 真有这种法
Texas statute? That a real law?
对
Yep.
罗密欧与茱丽叶是吧
Romeo and Juliet, huh?
知道他们的下场吗
You know how those two ended up?
相爱了
In love.
死了 你父母知道这事吗
Dead. Do your parents know about this?
你爸爸同意你找一个十七岁的女孩吗
Is your dad okay with you dating a 17-year-old girl?
我五岁时他就离家出走了
He took off when I was five,
要是碰见他我会问他
But if I ever bump into him, I'll ask him.
听我说 泰莎 我本来很相信你
You know, Tessa, I trusted you.
相信我什么
To what?
相信我不贪玩 不闯祸
Never have fun, take a risk,
做个像你一样的平凡少年
Be a normal teenager, like you?
我是你父亲好吗
I am your father, okay?
我可是拼了老命在呵护你呢
And I have been busting my ass to take care of you.
所以你就把那辆卡车开回家了
Is that what you were doing when you brought home the truck?
只要报告政府就没事了 可现在呢
All you had to do was report it, and now...
卢卡斯死了
Lucas is dead.
我的人生也完了
And my life is over.
谢谢你啊 你杷我照顾的可真好
Thank you. You've taken real good care of me.
求求你别开枪 求求你 爸
Please don't shoot me! Please! Dad!
他们可真下得去手啊
They were willing to kill her.
还是那副德行
Then they still are.
这幕后一定有人指使
Somebody somewhere gave that order.
我要去找些指纹来
I'm going to find some fingerprints.
别开枪
Please!
不 我是汽车人 我是汽车人
No! I'm an Autobot! I'm an Autobot!
拿上所有有用的东西 包括衣服
Grab whatever you think we can use for supplies. Clothes, anything.
把电脑也带上
And take that computer.
我们走
Let's go.
(洞中石屋)
真不好控制
This is not easy.
你总能做成点事吧
You know, you don't suck at everything, Dad.
这是什么
What the...
(拒绝 账号已锁定)
就知道会这样
I knew it.
你跟我说他是个普通人
You told me he was no one.
不过
Well,
这个普通人搞定了我们的高科技
this "no one" has our tech.
(我会找到你)
呼叫全体汽车人
Calling all Autobots.
喔 你碰哪儿了
Whoa! Oh, my God!
什么叫帅 什么叫酷 什么叫刺激啊
That was insane! It was awesome, but it was insane, right?
哦耶 太棒了
Oh, yeah! Hell, yeah!
他回来了 他还活着
He's back! He's alive!
擎天柱回来了
Optimus is here!
最后 我们终究迎来了希望
At last. There is hope after all.
自由星系的领导人回归了
Mr. Leader of the Free Galaxy is back.
我就知道你会来 这一点我从不怀疑
I knew you'd make it. I never doubted.
收到你的预警 我们一直在等待
We got your warning. We've been waiting.
没错 该爆发了 这帮老兄弟重新集结了
Hell, yeah. Boom time. We got the gang back together.
人类要求我们遵守他们的游戏规则
Humans have asked us to play by their rules.
但是 现在的规则已经改变了
Well, the rules have just changed.
人类 只会在背后捅你一刀
Human beings, bunch of backstabbin' weasels.
探长 你要坚守是非观
Hound, find your inner compass.
忠诚就像一朵脆弱的花
Loyalty is but a flower,
处于恐惧和诱惑的暴风中
In the winds of fear and temptation.
你在胡扯些什么
What the hell are you saying?
这是个俳句
It's a haiku.
少废话 否则我把手榴弹丢进你的喉咙
Cut the crap, before I drop a grenade down your throat.
你来啊 送死吧
Try it, you'll be dead.
好怕呀 快点下手吧
Oh, please pull it. Please do it.
快点吧 还能节省时间
You know what, it'll save us so much time.
对于这趟地球之旅
Well, raise your hand if you're thoroughly,
感到无福消受的人请举手
Disenchanted with our little pleasant Earth vacation.
这搭顺风车的人是谁
So, who's the stowaways?
干嘛拿抢对着我
Oh, whoa, hey, what's with the gun?
住手 探长 放下武器
Stop. Hound, both of you.
他们冒了生命危险救了我
They've risked their lives for mine.
我欠他们的
We owe them.
你们没有其他同伴的消息吗
So, there's been no sign of any others?
- 没有 - 只剩下我们几个了
- Nada. - We are all that's left.
人类想把我们一个个干掉
They're picking us off, one by one.
我们是可怜的四大金刚 加上你才五个
We're the pathetic, dirty foursome. And you make five.
就是说我们现在圆满了
So that's our best-case scenario?
永远得让汽车人罩着
Autobot witness protection?
我说赛车手 你想走沒人会拦你
Hey, Speed Racer, you're welcome to leave anytime.
好啊 那我先说清楚 超级奶爸
Well, for the record, Superdad,
我要跟也不是跟着你
I'm not hiding with you.
而是那边那位卡车师傅
I'm hiding out with that big guy.
擎天柱 你生死未卜 大黄蜂担任了指挥
Sensei, with your fate unknown, Bumblebee has held command,
不过这家伙太任性
Despite his complete,
完全沒有一个战士应有的素质
And total lack of anything resembling warrior discipline.
他就像个孩子
He's like a child.
- 这孩子正想教训你一下 - 你看你又冲动了
- This child is about to kick your ass. - He brings us shame.
跟我决斗 自作聪明
Cage fight. Smartass.
他们这是怎么了
What's the matter with them?
难道只有我看出他那双跟小狗一样的眼神
Am I the lone sage who sees through,
不过是伪装吗 你不称职
This puppy-dog eyes act? It's beneath you.
好极了 我一直在等他们自相残杀
Yes, I've been waiting for them all to dispatch each other,
这样我就可以不费劲当上老大
so I could take charge with no trouble at all.
然后他们都听我的指挥
Just me reporting to me.
看来他们没有你不行啊
Well, it sure looks like you've been missed.
汽车人 禁闭正在追杀我们
Autobots, Lockdown is hunting us,
而人类却在助纣为虐
And humans are helping.
我们必须搞清楚原因
We need to know why.
我不知道原因但我大概知道是谁
Well, listen, I don't know why, but I have an idea about who.
我扣下航拍机录下了突袭汽车人的画面
This drone I stole recorded footage of an Autobot raid.
画面断断续续的 但是你们仔细看
It's in pieces, but watch what happens here.
那不是救护车吗
Oh, that's Leadfoot.
他被扯成了碎片
They rip him apart.
一群野蛮人
Savages.
卡车上写着KSI建能科技公司
And later, this truck comes to haul him off. KSI. Kinetic Solutions.
世界上最大的军火空间技术承包商
Defense, aerospace, government contracts.
他们发明了这个
They designed this drone.
就是说政府把你们抓起来
So these government guys just hunt you down,
然后再交给KSI
And then pass you off to this KSI?
KSI总部在芝加哥
The company is headquartered in Chicago.
汽车人可能都被抓到那儿了
That could be where they were taken.
想进去就得大干一场
No way to get inside without a battle.
好啊 如果有人类帮忙呢
Well, what if you had some human help?
你们现在成搭档了
What, are you two partners now?
宝贝 我们也被追浦了
Sweetie, we're targets now, too.
不查个清楚我们脱不了身的
We need to know why or we'll never get our lives back.
各位 我曾发过誓永远不杀人类
Autobots, I have sworn to never kill humans.
你犯了个大错
Big mistake.
可一旦让我查出谁是幕后元凶
But when I find out who's behind this,
他必死无疑
he's going to die.
走你
Hooah!
(芝加哥)
既然我们已经被通缉了
There's a full-on manhunt out for us,
那就得定好新规矩
So we have some new rules.
带徽章的人都是我们的敌人
Anyone who has got a badge is not our friend.
我们要各个击破
We're gonna divide and conquer.
你们两个只负责准备食品等必须品
You two in charge of stealing food and the essentials. And nothing else.
KSI的芝加哥总部就像一个堡垒
Chicago KSI headquarters is like a fortress.
我们要打入他们绝密的军工部门
I'm gonna find a way into their top-secret military wing.
我得找个把柄要挟这个公司和政府
Find something to blackmail this company and the government.
让我们重回自由
We're gonna get our freedom back.
早安 乔伊斯先生
Good morning, Mr. Joyce.
是什么声音
What was that sound?
就是那个声音
That's "the" sound.
您要的那个声音
That you asked for.
不 我要的是无边无际 超凡脱俗
No, I asked for boundless. Transcendent.
我要一踏进这个大楼
When you walk through a door in this building,
就听起来像是踏入未来
It should sound like you've stepped into the future.
这是现在
Present.
这里呢
Say it.
是未来
Future.
过去是历史 现在是过去 而未来
The past is history. The present is past. The future is now.
我为什么联络不到你
Why can't I get in touch with you?
你难道不了解北扱的发现代表什么吗
Don't you realize what the Arctic find means?
还记得我们小时候听到的故事吗
You know that story we were all told as children,
一颗巨大的小行星
About a giant asteroid that struck the Earth,
几百万年前撞击地球导致恐龙灭绝
Millions of years ago and wiped out the dinosaurs?
大概还记得
Vaguely.
我们都错了 是这块金属导致恐龙灭绝的
We were wrong. This metal caused the great extinction.
具体原因还不清楚
How and why, I can't yet say.
但同位素检测确定
But carbon dating puts,
时间点为公元前六干五百万年
It at 65 million years B.C.
你要我们挖的这个矿
This ore you've got us digging for,
比你相像的还要危险
Is a lot more dangerous than you think.
而且我的人...
And my people...
达茜
Darcy,
我觉得你这趟在外面跑太久了
I think that you've been out in the field for far too long.
恐龙的事等晩餐再聊吧
Why don't we discuss dinosaurs over dinner?
想吃肋排吗
Ribs?
算了吧你
Not a chance.
你想都想不到我们取得了什么进展
You have no idea what's been happening here.
这会是一项跨时代的进步
We're about to make the quantum leap.
这是一种稀土金属
A rare-earth metal.
分子结构非常的不稳定
Molecularly unstable.
大规模的产业应用还没开始
Industrial uses, none.
然后外星人来了
And then the aliens came.
我们就发现了其中的关联
And we made the connection.
他们就是这个造的
It's what they're made of.
这就是我们梦寐以求的
It's the Holy Grail.
我们称之为 变形元素
"Transformium." That's what we're calling it.
这名字不错 通俗 已经注册商标了
Focus-grouped. Catchy. Trademarked.
是的 这是继分裂原子以来
Yeah. This is the greatest advance in modern physics,
在现代物理学领域 最为伟大的进步
since the splitting of the atom.
这种物质是可编程的
It's programmable matter.
我们排列了它的基因组
And now, we've mapped its genome.
- 是我 - 对 是你排的
- I. - Now you've mapped its genome.
而现在我们可以开始来对它进行
And now we can begin to give it
指令的下达
instructions.
这不是一般的好东西
This is extremely good.
看仔细了
Watch this.
我们能把它从一种形态变成任何其它的形态
We can change anything into anything.
就像有感官一样对吧
Sensual, almost. Don't you think?
喜欢音乐
Do you like music?
就让他变成音响
The Pill.
或者是暴力武器什么的
Perhaps something a little more violent?
哦 天哪 你做到了
Oh, my God. You've done it.
这可以应用于航天 应用于军队
In aerospace, the military...
我们将称霸整个机器人产业
We will own the entire robotics industry.
开拓所有领域
All exploration.
包括在海底 在太空 应有尽有
The oceans. Space. Everything.
温布利 这是什么
Wembley. What is this?
广告 这就是你要的那个水母广告
The jellyfish commercial that you wanted.
你形容他们像女人一样又诱惑又致命
You said they were erotic yet deadly, like women.
我从没那么说
I never said that.
是的 你说过
Yes, you did.
没 就是没说
No, I didn't.
你绝对说过 相信我
I definitely heard you say it.
你当时在说你的前女友
'cause you were talking about your ex-girlfriend,
说她人很性感 也很贱
who was sexy, but a bitch.
参观过程中别吃东西
Please don't eat on the tour.
该不会是她吧
Is that her?
嘿 我找了好几箱的衣服
Hey, I found a whole bunch of boxes of clothes.
宝贝 你可以穿这些宽松的长裤
So, sweetie, you can get some long pants, nice, loose-fitting ones,
别穿那些超短裤了好吗
And lose the short shorts, okay?
你们都拿了些什么
What'd you guys get?
蛋白粉
It's protein.
我说只拿必需品就行了
Look, I said the essentials, okay?
容易吗我们 差点被抓
It wasn't easy. We almost got caught.
你还偷了漱口水
You stole mouthwash?
跟你女儿接吻时要口气清新
I like to be fresh when I'm making out with your daughter.
你可真逗
That's funny.
这事是不可能的 永远不可能
Yeah, that's not happening ever.
永远
Ever?
我想让你看看我的杰作 惊破天
This is our military prototype, Galvatron.
真是搞不懂
I don't understand it.
已经重置五次了
This is the fifth iteration.
为什么结果还是这样
Why does he keep turning out like this?
最终版本只是有些小瑕疵
It's just some bugs in the final render.
惊破天 我是照着擎天柱的样子设计的
I modeled Galvatron after Optimus Prime.
可为什么他看起来还是像威震天
Why does he keep looking like Megatron?
生产序列即将完成
Rendering sequence is almost finished. Stand by.
只是简单的代码编写
Simple coding.
什么算法呢
Algorithms!
什么数学呢
Math!
我们为什么没有办法 按照我们的想法
Why can't we make what we want to make,
做出我们想要的东西来
the way we want to make it?
为什么
Why?
这张脸消费者看了会喜欢吗
And does that look like a consumer-friendly face to you?
还有胸口那个大洞是怎么回事
And what about that big hole in the chest?
就是觉得很霸气 我喜欢
I think it's bad-ass. I like it.
我也喜欢
Love it.
可我讨厌他
Well, I hate it.
哦 瞧他来了 这个光头版的科学怪人
Oh, here he is. That bald-headed Doc Frankenstein.
女士 他们这可是违法的 这是非法实验活动
Ma'am, this is not legal. This is illegal experimentation.
外星人不会对人类做这种事
Aliens would never do this to people!
最多也就是把你吃掉 弄死
Eat you, kill you, maybe, but that's it.
这是不对的 不能把我关在盒子里
This ain't right! Nobody puts baby in a box!
啊
Ahhh!
这比水刑还要残忍
This is worse than waterboarding!
这位迷你先生在帮我们翻译
This little gentleman has been translating for us,
那两颗脑袋里的所有信息
All the information that comes from these two heads.
他们的历史 他们的科学以及一切知识
Their history, their science, everything.
那不就是威震天吗
Is that Megatron?
没错 他就是
Precisely.
这都是怎么弄到的
Where did you get all this?
是特殊的政府承包项目
Special government contract.
现在我们知道变形金刚的所有秘密
Now we know everything about Transformers.
我们现在可以自主打造变形金刚了
And now at long last we can build them ourselves.
而且会更完美
And we can build them better.
对 很好 大黄蜂 太棒了
Yeah, that's good, Bee. That'll get us in.
每天都有好几拨车被运进KSI
A couple times a day, these guys are moving in vehicle shipments into KSI,
并作扫描处理
For something called canning."
而且安保措施滴水不漏
Major security all over.
但我们可以拿这个机密研究大楼的入口下手
So our best shot at getting in is a back classified research entrance.
我们早晨开大黄蜂进去
I'm gonna drive in with Bee tomorrow morning.
打扰一下 你们别在我面前亲热好吧
Excuse me. There's no smooching in front of me, okay?
您可真是老古板 现在谁还用亲热这个词啊
You're so square. Who even says "smooching"?
一点都不受尊重
I tell you, no respect.
有时候你是一点办法都没有
It's just impossible sometimes.
是啊 大黄蜂也曾给我这种感觉
Yeah. I went through that with Bumblebee.
沉住气 要沉住气
Calm down. Calm down.
听着 在这关键时刻应该内心冷酷
You know, at a time like this, the idea is to keep cool,
而不是外表耍酷 所以把眼镜给摘了
Not look cool, so why don't you lose the glasses?
大概一个月前
About a month ago,
我大半夜里听到家里有动静 是不是你
middle of the night, I thought I heard noises in my house. Was that you?
什么 拜托 不可能
What? Come on. No way.
别唬弄我小子
Don't lie to me, kid.
你看那个拿枪的人
You see that guy with the gun out there?
这好多人都拿着枪
There's so many guys with guns.
下车告诉他
Let's get out of the car and tell him.
我们要闯进去
We're about to break in and it's your idea,
我可不怕 我老了 早就活够本了
'cause I don't care. I'm old, I've already lived long enough.
你说话不挑时候 不分场合
You have a really bad habit of having,
这个臭毛病真的很不讲究
These conversations at the wrong time, man.
是你去来文的 还是我去来武的
You want to come clean or you want me to make a mess?
好吧 先生...
Sir, can I talk to you for a second, please?
他没跟你说话 是跟我 跟我
It was me, it was me, it was me, it was me.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
这是要扫描的车吗
Taking it in for scanning?
好 可以过去了
All right. You're good to go.
我饶不了你 臭小子
I'm literally gonna kill you.
正在扫描三号库位
Scanning in bay three.
我们汲取所有外星科技精华
We took old, alien technology
并在所有方面实现超越
And made it better in every way.
向您介绍"毒刺"
Introducing Stinger.
KSI "我扪缔造着世界"
KSI. We make the world.
那就是他们的超级机器人
That is a bad-ass robot.
挺像你的 大黄蜂
He kind of looks like you, Bee.
这就是组成部件
Here is the past. And now the future.
他们自行打造新版本
They're trying to build their own versions.
起码他们看起来比这辆酷
Well, at least they're picking cooler cars than this.
- 你怎么说话的 - 停下
- You talk to me like that? - Bee, stop!
这就是自作聪明的下场
You see what happens from being a wiseass?
给我滚出去
Now get out of here.
"毒刺"灵感来源于大黄蜂
Stinger, inspired by Bumblebee,
但实现了全线飞跃
But better in every way.
你这混蛋
Son of a...
不不不 你冷静点 他受刺激了
No, no! You gotta calm down.
停下
He's crazy! Stop!
别这样 大黄蜂 你把动静闹的太大了
Bumblebee! Bee, stop going psycho!
所以现在我们没有足够的Transformer做生产*
Our factory does not have enough transformium for production...
知道吗 很晩了 是你晩了 是你
...because you don't keep your promise to supply it.
我亲爱的玫瑰花 你一生气我就弄不懂你
My delicate flower, I can't understand you when you're angry.
其实你说什么我一点都听不懂
Actually, I don't really understand you at all.
我们已经没有足够的变形元素用于...
Our entire factory is up and running...
对不起 稍等一下 嘿
Excuse me one second. Hey!
嘿 你们俩 手脚够快的
Hey, you two! Grease monkeys.
你们在搞什么名堂
What the hell is going on here? Huh?
老爷车怎么开这儿来了
What's with this vintage crap?
我们可不收废旧老爷车
We're not scanning collector car junk.
难道你们不了解我们所从事的工作吗
What do you think it is that we make here? Hmm?
我们可是在作诗 我们是诗人 懂吗
We make poetry. We're poets. All right?
你给我打工 可以犯错
You work for me, you get one mistake.
- 但是只要一次 不能再这样了 - 好吧
- One. Understood? It won't happen again. - It certainly won't.
现在让这个可悲的破烂给我消失 还有
So let's get this pathetic thing out of here.
你们也消失
And you, too.
真报歉 非常报歉 我们走吧
So sorry. So sorry. Let's move on.
看着他 我进去查查 回去告诉其它人
Watch him. I'm going to see what I can find. Quietly get out of here.
我受不了你生气的样子
I swear. I swear. I can't bear it when you're angry.
你知道我有多纠结吗
You know how it upsets me.
大黄蜂 你必须马上冷静下来
Bee, you gotta calm down right now.
好的 冷静
I'm perfectly calm, dude.
随你试深呼吸或者其它什么方法都可以
You gotta breathe, or just do whatever it is that you do.
我可冷静了 我不会碰它的
I'm calm. I'm calm. I'm not even touching it.
你看我基本上没碰它 没挨着
Okay, I'm barely touching it. I'm barely touching it.
快点变回车子 快点
Oh, my God. Turn back into a car right now!
别在我眼前晃悠
Get out of my face, all right?
欢迎我们的设计团队 就从大黄蜂开始吧
Our design team, started with the Bumblebee
这个外星机器人的设计即破旧又过时
But really, this alien's design was decrepit and, let's face it,
纯属古董
Antique.
就是一堆破铜烂铁
What the...
别冲动 大黄蜂 他们是闹着玩的
Don't take it personally, Bee.
就是一个丑字
You mean ugly.
- 哦 见鬼去吧 - 不 不
- Oh, hell, no! - No! No!
性能比我还好是吧
You think you're better than me!
你刚才踫了什么
What did you touch?
十五分钟以后到我的办公室去
My office in 15 minutes.
这里是七号分解室
This is dissection room seven.
进行惊破天第十二次事后分析
Galvatron, render postmortem number 12.
延续第三十二次事件后进行的头部拆解
Continued head disfigurement at event number 32.
这买卖怎么样 可以吗
So what about the deal? Is it done?
你拿到种子了吗
Did you get the Seed?
会拿到的 抓住擎天柱就有了
We get it when the bounty hunter gets Prime.
好 不过这事也有复杂性
Meanwhile, there has been a complication.
等等 你刚才说什么性
A what?
不 在KSI我们不用那样的词
No, no. At KSI, we don't use words like that.
一个窝藏汽车人的平民
A civilian harboring the Autobots has,
黑了你的迷你航拍机
Hacked into one of your mini-drones.
你的事情 他们应该知道
Meaning, they may know of your involvement.
什么
What?
真是让人捏一把冷汗
That was a little bit intense.
我需要更多的变形元素 我现在就要
I need more Transformium, and I need it now,
不然做不出更多原型来
To build more prototypes.
去告诉你的外星赏金猎人
You tell your alien bounty hunter,
我把整个公司整个身家都赌在这个买卖上了
That I have staked my company on this deal.
而我赌的是我的性命
And I have merely staked my life.
嘿 这事当初是你找我的 记得吗
Hey, you came to me on this, remember?
你从中情局退休之后
You retire from the CIA,
从我们公司拿到了七位数
You get a seven-figure piece of my company,
然后你我联手改造这个国家的国防事业
And you and I revolutionize national defense together.
可是 艾汀杰
But, Attinger,
伙计 为了我们两个都好
Buddy, for both our sakes,
你必须要弄到那个种子
You need to deliver the Seed.
我进去了 有我摄像头的画面吗
I'm in. Can you see my camera?
他们在拆解救护车
They're melting Ratchet.
他们残害了救护车
They slaughtered Ratchet!
我要把他们撕成碎片
I'm gonna tear them apart!
金属
Metal.
我一直觉得 他们就是一堆金属
Just metal. That's what I always thought of them.
并不是 他们像我们一样有生命和灵魂
Well, they're not. They're living things, with souls like ours.
我曾和其中的一个说过话
Once, I spoke to one.
你研究变形元素
And you're working with Transformium?
呃 是 你说得对 这是我的工作 没错
Uh, yeah, that's what I do. I am.
我负责挖掘它 但已经沒有什么好挖的了
I'm out there digging for it. There's just not much left to find.
你们还真缺原料啊
So that's how badly you boys need more, huh?
沦落到要把邪恶的霸天虎分解掉
Reduced to melting evil old Decepticons down.
不 他是汽车人
No. That's an Autobot there.
曾是为人类奋战的一方
The ones who fought for us.
好了 这件事我来处理
I've got this taken care of from here. Right.
两个安检门扫到了同样的身份条形码
Same badge code scanned at two separate gates.
我要封锁机密区域
I'm having the classified area locked down now.
盘查那个人
Check that guy.
嗨
Hey!
给我站住
Stop right there!
嗨 说你呢
Stop!
别动
Freeze!
给我趴在墙上
Up against the wall.
好吧
All right.
要知道 商业间谍可是重罪 伊格先生
Corporate espionage. That's a very serious crime, Mr. Yeager.
听着 我要找律师
Look, I want a lawyer.
找司法部或者是我可以信赖的人
The Justice Department. Somebody I can trust.
要伤害我家人的不是你的公司
I'm just trying to protect my family, okay? Not from your company,
而是政府
From the government.
伊格先生
Mr. Yeager,
你以为我替谁工作
Who do you think I work for?
你保护家人的决心让我敬佩
You're trying to protect your family, that's admirable.
但我要保卫国家不受外星战争侵害
I'm trying to defend the nation from alien war.
我们吃过苦头
We've had a taste of what that looks like,
不能再重蹈覆辙
And we are not gonna tolerate another.
现在
Now...
我们今天的谈话会有两种结局
There is a version of this conversation,
一是你回到你的谷仓
Where you get to go back to your barn,
你女儿光荣毕业
Your daughter gets to graduate with honors,
接着过你的正常生活
And life as you know it will go on.
这里的事情就当什么也没有发生过
You have no idea what you're involved with here.
是吗
Really?
那另一种结局是什么
What's the other version of this conversation?
是你派手下人来谋杀我的女儿
The one when you send in the hired help to murder my little girl?
还是像个爷们那样自己动手
Or you gonna man up and do it yourself?
那你喜欢哪一种
What's your preference?
我只问你一次
I'm going to ask you this once.
擎天柱在哪里
Where is Optimus Prime?
快点 我们离开这里
Come on. Let's get out of here.
我们走 去地下室
We're moving. Basement.
他们来了
They're here.
都给我出去
Get out! All of you!
科学大会结束了 摧毁实验室
Science fair's over, meatbags! Destroy the lab!
闪开 小心 小心
Move, Look out! Look out!
全都给我毁掉
Destroy it all!
危险 发现安全漏洞 危险
Danger! Security breach! Danger...
伙计们是我啊 快把我从这鬼地方弄出去
Guys! It's me! Break me out of this Frankenstein box!
嘿 嘿 住手
Hey! Stop!
那可是公司的财产
That's company property!
他们可不是你的个人财产
They're not your property!
他们是我的朋友
They were my friends.
你还敢啰嗦 探长现在可就在你面前呢
Oh, you ain't talking so much now! You got Hound in front of you, huh?
那就来啊 让我瞧瞧你们有什么本事
Go ahead. Show us your true colors, once and for all.
只要你给我个信号 我就碾碎他
Just give me the word, I'll splatter him.
请告诉这位杀红眼的仁兄
Why don't you tell Itchy Fingers here,
这些都是战争的牺牲品 是死掉的金属
That this is all the spoils of war. Dead metal.
我们用它创新 我们所从事的可是科学
Innovation. What we do here is science.
因为即便我们不做 别人也会做
Because if we don't do it, somebody else will.
因为科技是你无法阻挡的
Because you cannot stop technology!
我们可不是你的什么科技
We're not your technology!
让我废了这个混蛋
Let me vaporize his ass.
我破解了密码
I broke the code.
我有你们的基因组
I own your whole genome.
全世界都会知道你做了什么
The world will know what you're doing here.
全世界 全世界都会认同我
The world? The world will approve.
人类可以造变形金刚 你还不明白
We can make you now. Don't you get it?
我们不需要你们了 再也不需要
We don't need you anymore.
现实太骨感
That was cruel.
走吧 汽车人
Autobots,
沒我们的事了
we're done.
这就走了 也不给他们点颜色瞧瞧
We're done? We're not gonna kick a little bit of ass?
我差点忍不住弄死他
I've been itching to kill something lately.
这是个大好机会
This is our chance.
我们要阻止他 你必须阻止他
We have to stop him. You have to stop him.
这个从没实战检验过
It's never been tested in the field.
只是在实验室和军事基地 还没上过大街
Labs, military bases, but not on civilian streets.
国防部的承包商刚遭到攻击
Down there a Defense Department contract,
这可是恐怖装击
Was just attacked in a terrorist attack.
现在中情局要采取军事行动
This is now a CIA military op.
沒人追究你 快动手吧
You're indemnified. Respond!
我们走
Let's go.
芝加哥 KSI 连接距离最近的卫星
KSI Chicago, closest live sat, patch it in.
我们无端遭受汽车人的攻击
Been an unprovoked Autobot attack.
现在出动惊破天
Bring up Galvatron.
惊破天 开始变形
Transforming Galvatron.
惊破天 正在启动
Galvatron coming online.
启动"毒刺"
Bring up Stinger.
"毒刺"正在启动
Stinger coming online.
让那些外星恐怖分子见识一下
Let's show these alien terrorists,
我们升级技术的厉害
What an upgrade looks like.
惊破天和毒刺正在去拦截目际的途中
Galvatron and Stinger are moving to intercept targets.
报告 五个目标出现 图橡清晰
Reapers. Five targets in the open. Good picture.
两英里 准备拦截
Two miles to intercept.
还有两百米
200 meters.
预备
Engage.
变形
Transform.
哇哦
Whoa.
这都是我们编程操控的吗
We are programming this, right?
是的 大部分是的
Yes. Mostly.
系统无法工作
Systems seem to have malfunctioned.
锁定那五个目标
Targeting five bogeys.
做好发射准备
Engaging rockets.
即将发射
Missiles away.
快跑 大黄蜂 快跑
Gotta haul ass, Bee! Come on!
毒刺正在追击
Stinger is in pursuit.
走火了 走火了 打错了 打错了
Misfire, misfire! Misfire, misfire!
系统出现错误 惊破天擅自发射四枚火箭弹
System failure. Galvatron just fired four rockets.
我去 他们玩真的
Whoa! They're shooting at us!
哇 哇 哇 哇 哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
这是怎么回事
Watch out! What are you doing?
谁
What was that?
我们现在需要一个整建制的医疗队
We need a full medical team now.
可能会有平民伤亡
Possible civilian casualties.
那辆车里座的可是平民
I mean, you got a lot of people in the crossfire here. I don't like...
你正在为国家和世界创造历史
You're making history here. For your country, for the world.
人类的自由正芨岌可危
Human freedom is at stake.
无辜的人牺牲 那是常有的
Innocent people die all the time.
快呀 擎天柱
Come on, Optimus!
泰莎
Tessa!
让他反击 不能倒下 使劲打
Make him fight. Don't let him go down. Make him fight!
快过来 快出来
Come on, come on. Come on, come on.
泰莎 泰莎
Tessa! Tessa!
快到地里去 泰莎
Tessa, run to the field!
你根本就没有灵魂
You have no soul!
正因为如此 我毫无畏惧
That is why I have no fear!
你去死吧
You die!
快来救我
Help me!
那是什么东西
What is that?
那是我的安排
That's my asset.
把惊破天叫回来
Pull Galvatron back.
快去
Do it.
是你
Are you!
我得去救她
I got to go get her.
泰莎
Tessa!
别过去 他会杀了你
Don't go out there! He'll kill you!
我要去救泰莎
She needs my help!
她已经藏好了
She's hidden!
擎天柱 要挺住要挺住啊
Optimus! Optimus, get up, get up!
我不行了 快离开这里
I can't. Get out of here.
我很为你惋惜 擎天柱
I feel sorry for you, Prime.
你对人类太忠心了
Your allegiance to these humans.
效忠的本质问题就是
The trouble with loyalty to a cause,
那个你效忠的对象注定迟早都会背叛你
Is that the cause will always betray you.
是谁派你来的
Who sent you here?
你真知道你的来历吗
Where do you think you came from?
你是被生下来的
You think you were born?
不是 你是被制造出来的
No. You were built.
现在你的造物主要召你回去
And your creators want you back.
我们是各为其主
We all work for someone.
不 不
No, no.
不
No.
他要抓她
It's got her!
- 离开车子 - 泰莎
- She's in the car! - Tessa!
- 不 - 泰莎
- No! - Tessa!
爸爸
Dad!
泰莎 快出来 快出来
Tessa, get out! Get out!
泰莎
Tessa!
快出来 泰莎
Get out! Tessa!
- 爸爸 救我 - 泰莎
- Dad, help me! - Tessa!
快来救我 爸爸 爸
Help me, help me! Dad! Dad!
爸爸 爸爸
Dad! Dad!
打碎玻璃 打碎玻璃出来
Tessa! Break the glass! Break the glass to get out!
我在打呢
I'm trying!
- 泰莎 我抓不住了 - 爸爸
- Tessa, I can't hold on! - Dad!
- 泰莎 快打碎玻璃 快打碎玻璃 - 救我
- Tessa! Just break it! Break the glass! - Help me!
泰...
Tess...
凯德 向汽车人发出警报
Cade, warn the Autobots!
救我 别丢下我
Dad, help me! Don't leave me!
泰莎
No!
把那个人类扔到垃圾堆去
Take that human to the trash.
国防部长先生 我的小队出发了
Mr. Secretary. My team is on the way.
这回是中情局的行动
This is a CIA operation.
这些都是我安排好的
This is my asset.
告诉他们先撤退
Tell the military to stand down.
稍等 白宫来电了
Hang on, I have the White House.
哎呀 探长 你可算接电话了
Agent, hello! Oh, my goodness. Boy,
白宫里已经乱成一锅粥了
Is it a flurry of excitement over here at the White House.
所有人都气急败坏的 都在冲我发火
Everybody is super, super mad. At me.
我查了上次的会议记录
So, I went over my notes from our last meeting,
可我不记得你提过会出现现在这种
And I'm not sure when you said anything,
巨型外星战舰降落密歇根大街呀
About a "giant alien warship over Michigan Avenue."
告诉总统 这并不是攻击
Tell the President this is not an attack.
记得这艘飞船吗 擎天柱
Remember this ship, Prime?
这是为了你们这些远征骑士
Built for all you Knights, you great crusaders,
探索宇宙而建造的
To explore the universe.
不过我夺取了控制权
Well, I commandeered it.
现在它是我掌控的监狱了
It's my personal prison now.
擎天柱
Optimus?
欢迎回到骑士的光荣圣殿 擎天柱
Welcome back to the Knights' Temenos, Prime.
你已经让它蒙羞了
You have disgraced it.
快和你那帮忘命天涯的小混们汇合吧
Join your fellow rebels, fugitive scum.
这里专门收藏稀有的品种
It's for the rarest of specimens. The worst of the worst.
都是恶棍中的恶棍
It's taken centuries,
我已经收集了所有的骑士 就差你了
But I've collected all the Knights but you.
造物主想把他的棋子清理干净
The creators want to sweep their chessboard clean.
我是不会被任何人奴役的
I'm slave to no one.
因为这些种群相互搅和在一起
All this species mixing with species.
才会打破宇宙的平衙
It upsets the cosmic balance.
造物主们并不喜欢这样
The creators, they don't like it.
他们造你就是让你按他们的意思办事
They built you to do what you were told.
快 它还没有起飞
Why hasn't it taken off yet?
快 大黄蜂 他们在下降 我们上去
Come on, Bee, it's descending. You got to get on it!
任务已经完成 擎天柱在禁闭手上
Savoy, mission accomplished. Lockdown has Prime.
现在办正事吧
The deal's going down now.
我们去接头地点把种子拿回来
Picking up the Seed at the recon point.
已经看见降落区了
Nest, Talon. L.Z. appears clear.
我很享受这次猎杀
Much as I've enjoyed the hunt,
但我不喜欢这破败的星球
I won't miss your wretched planet.
就这么成交吧 以擎天柱换种子
Our deal is done. One Prime for one Seed.
可要小心保护它呀
Handle it with care.
我相信你们人类已经准备好了
I trust your species is ready.
我们人类不用你担心
Don't worry about our species.
再会啦 地球
Farewell, Earth.
快跑 快跑啊 快跑啊 快跑
Come on, come on!
大黄蜂
Bee, come on!
没错 这个主意太糟了
It's a bad idea.
但我就是喜欢这个糟糕的主意
But I'm all about bad ideas.
抄家伙 走你
Let's go!
好吧 那就走
Well, let's rock.
这下玩大了
This is crazy.
如果你想撤你就撤
Look, you wanna cut and run, you better do it now.
我是不会放弃的
I'm gonna die trying.
我不是来帮你救女儿的
Hey, I'm not here to help you get your daughter.
我是要你帮我救女朋友
You're here to help me get my girlfriend.
准备启动暗物质引擎 开足马力
Engage dark-matter drives. Full power.
我们现在深入敌后了
We're behind enemy lines now.
禁闭的船很多陷阱 眼睛睁大点
Lockdown's ship has booby traps. Eyes open.
小心那些碎骨机 大脑麻痹仪
Beware of his bone grinders, brain blinders,
触感探测仪 染色体修改器
Flesh peelers, chromosomal inverters,
精神分裂泥 黑洞陷阱门 当然还有辐射
catatonic sludge, black hole trapdoors, and, of course, radiation.
动作必须要快 我们要杀他个措手不及
We must be quick. We have the element of surprise.
暴力对我们来说是万不得已的手段
Let's try to use violence as a last resort.
搞定它
Oh, get it!
我要杀了你 杀了你
I kill you! Kill you!
我讨厌那种东西
Ugh. I hate those things.
真可怕
That's freaky.
他已经被弄死了
He's not alive anymore.
好 看完了 他们不在这 走吧
Well, we looked. They're not here. Let's go.
什么 找不到泰莎 我是不会走的
What'? Hey, I'm not going anywhere without Tessa.
那么你告诉我 有我什么好处
I'm unclear. What's in it for me?
有你什么好处
What's in it for you?
你 别激动 有话好好说
Easy. Let's use words.
对你的好处 就是我不会杀了你
What's in it for you is I don't kill you.
我们得救出老大 还有那个女孩 明白吗
We're getting the boss back. And the girl. Copy?
好吧 你真有说服力 男子气概堪称典范
Okay, okay. Very persuasive. Textbook machismo.
看这点 我不搞点破坏是不行了
Well, then. We'll need to sabotage something.
最好快点 因为暗物质驱动器就要启动了
Better hurry. Because dark-matter drives are preparing to take off.
太好了
Oh, wonderful.
我们只有十分钟
I give us 10 minutes.
这不会就是这个引擎运转的声音吧
Is that what that sound is? The engines filling up?
你该不会说这艘飞船
Are you telling me that thing's gonna be...
再过十分钟就要飞走吧 十分钟
This is gonna be flying out of here in 10 minutes? Ten minutes?
只有九分钟 也许七分钟
Could be nine. Worst case, seven.
人类 你们去搜牢房
Humans, search the cell blocks.
别浪费时间 快走
We're wasting time, let's go.
- 我们去找中心部分 - 开始行动
- We'll find the center core. - Let's move.
咱们把这艘破船停下来
We're gonna stop this nightmare ship.
这么大的船上怎么找她
We're never gonna find her in this huge ship.
根本就是大海捞针
Like a needle in a haystack.
泰莎
Tessa!
这下好了
Great. Great.
你真高明啊 相当高明啊
Oh, that was smooth. No, that was really smooth,
昭告天下我们在这儿
Letting everybody know we're here.
你生怕他们发现不了我们
Now they're gonna be looking for us.
最好快点 十字线 要赶在进宇宙之前
Better hurry, Crosshairs, before we go into space!
原来那颗"小甜枣"在这里
Ah. Here's the little jujube right here.
你好 小宝贝
Hello, Mama.
是谁把锚抛下去的
Who fired the anchors?
谁入侵了我的飞船 有人要越狱了
Who's on my ship? We have a loose prisoner.
快把他们找出来
快点
Hurry up.
我们只有六分钟了
We got like six minutes.
会找到她的
We'll find her.
等一下
Hold up.
快往回走
Back up.
快点 他们会发现我们的
Come on, these things are gonna find us. Hurry, hide.
有武器
Weapons!
快来帮我 快点快点
Come here. Help me. Hurry, hurry.
帮我上去
Help me up.
外面是什么鬼声音
There are some weird sounds out there.
接着
Get!
那是什么动静
What is that?
不知道
I don't know.
准备好了吗
You ready?
跑
Run.
我们不能坐以待毙
All right, we're not going down without a fight.
他们一转过来就拿下他们
They turn that corner, and we're gonna take them.
你不会愉着跑了吧
You ready or you gonna bitch out on me?
不 我不会跑的
No, I got your back.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
不好也得好
Absolutely.
别逃跑 准备好了吗
Don't bitch out on me. Are you ready?
好了 好了 好了
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
上
Whoa, okay!
我投降
I surrender!
我真的很抱歉 我真的真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry! I'm so, so, so sorry!
你怎么能这样
What'd you do? How'd you do that?
我整个都懵了
I have no idea!
孬种 没用的胆小鬼
You no-good, chickenshit little rat!
你看见了吗 你看见了吗
Look at that. You see that? Oh!
留在这 你这个废物
You stay here, Lucky Charms!
太牛了 得拿这个申请个专利啊
Oh, man. I am so gonna patent this shit.
泰莎
Tess!
爸爸 救我
Dad! Help me!
- 嗨 泰莎 - 泰莎
- Hey! Tess? - Tess!
快 快跑
Come on, move, move!
泰莎
Tessa!
我爱死你了肖恩 你救了我 你救了我
Shane, I love you! I love you! You saved me! You saved me!
我知道 好了
I know. I know.
谢谢你 多夸你救了我
Thank you. Thank you so much.
- 太谢谢你了 - 嗯 是他救了你
- Thank you. You saved me. - Oh, yeah, he saved you. Yeah.
好吧
Yeah.
你和你的投降先生有很多话要聊
I think you and Mr. "I Surrender" have a lot to catch up about, sweetie.
他也救了我 你看他多威猛啊
He saved me, too. You should have seen him in there.
好了大英雄 快走吧 快走
I mean, our hero. Let's go. Now.
看仔细点
Eyes open.
我这就要打开了
I almost got it.
兄弟们快进去 走 走 走
Big boy coming through! Go, Go, Go,
这应该是个超级大牢房
This has got to be the Supermax.
别放过角落
Watch the corners.
有不少笼子
There's a lot of cages.
里面都是可怕的动物
Oh, yeah. Creepy critters in here.
我才不想知道谁住过这大笼子
I don't want to know what's in the big cage.
这是什么呀
What's this?
探长 别这么干
Hound, don't do it.
你你看起来危害性没这么大
Aw, you don't look very dangerous in there.
噢 那东西真是 恶心的让人想吐
Oh, that's festering ugliness.
我受伤了 鼻子在融化 被灼伤了
I'm hit! I'm down! It's melting! It burns!
这是酸 真恶心
Ugh, I think it's acid! Ah, nuts.
感觉像是一坨屎
It's just shizzle.
但愿它不传染
I hope that's not contagious.
我非得收拾你一顿 你活着只会让人恶心
I got to hurt you now. You're just too disturbing to live.
去死吧 垃圾
Take that, bitch!
你完了
Oh! You're dead.
探长
Hound!
是擎天柱 擎天柱你在哪儿
He's alive! Optimus, sound off!
在这儿 快点
In here, quick!
挺住 我们来救你
Hang on, we're coming for you!
这是骑士飞船的逃生仓 我们可以离开了
The arms of this Knight Ship detach! We can break free!
他的船身是独立的 快
It's a separate ship! Hurry!
驾驶舱在哪边 左还是右
Where's the cockpit? Right or left?
- 右边 - 让我来开
- Right! - I'm on it, boss.
得快点 快没时间了
Hurry. We have no time.
擎天柱 我来啦
Sensei. Let's rock!
我早就想开这家伙了 我就位了
I always wanted to fly one of these things. I'm there, boss!
嘿 我说伊格工程师
Hey, Yeager Technologies,
你研究出来怎么逃跑了吗
You gonna invent us a way out of this one?
- 不是吧 - 我的天哪
- Whoa. - Oh, my God.
我做不到 我做不到
I am not doing this. I am not doing that.
我能行
Yes, we are.
没事 它很稳 来吧
No, it's good. It's stable. Come on.
我才不要
No way.
宝贝 有我在呢 我会保护你的
Sweetie, you know why I'm here? I'm here to protect you.
我才不相信你呢
You've done great at that.
你必须相信我 下去 快
I want you to trust me right now. We're getting down. Let's go.
别往下看 好吗
Don't look down, okay?
往前看 你看这并不难 往前走
Step. See, it's easy. Come on.
小心 这缆绳越往前越细了
Careful, these cables are starting to get thinner here!
往前走 往前走 对
Step. Step. There.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
接着往前走 别往下看 宝贝
See, don't look down! All right? Don't look down.
我们就要到对面的大楼了
We're gonna be at the building in no time!
没事吧 泰莎 接着往前走
You okay, Tess? Keep stepping.
天哪 天哪 老爸 我的天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God, Dad! Oh!
宝贝 在这儿别停下来好吗
All right, sweetie. You need to keep moving here, okay?
过来
Come on!
不行 我都吓懵了
I can't. I'm freaking out.
你现在必须爬过来
You need to move now!
我才不要 我要回到船上去
I'm not moving! I'm going back to the ship!
见鬼 你不能回到船上去
Oh, shit!
你做什么事都跟我反着 对吗
You can't go back to the ship, honey!
你看着吧
Watch me!
你现在既然不到十八岁就必须按我说的做
You are not 18 years old yet and you're gonna do what I say!
你给我过来
Now let's go!
我们要往这边走 好吗 不是那边
We need to go this way, okay. Not that way.
劝劝你的朱丽叶 罗密欧
Talk to her, Romeo! Now!
你就听你爸一次吧
Come on, for God's sake.
你别跟着瞎掺和
Do not start with me.
天哪 那是什么东西啊
Oh, my God, what is that?
听我说 泰莎 不要往回看
All right, Tessa. Don't look back.
你别这么说 我现在要转身了
Well, don't say that to me. Now I want to turn around.
没什么大不了的 宝贝
It's nothing major, sweetie.
你这么说肯定不是什么小事
Well, that means it's totally major!
我会把枪对准你的方向
I'm gonna have to point this gun in your direction.
看起来像瞄准你 实际上不是
It's gonna feel like it's in your direction, but I'm not.
你最好快点
You better hurry.
你想杀了我吗
Are you trying to kill me?
为了上这条船我老命都豁出去了
I had to bust my ass to get up here on this spaceship!
- 开枪啊 - 快趴下
- Shoot it! - Get down now!
别怕 泰莎 爸爸来了
Tessa, wait! I'm coming for you!
泰莎 坚持住
Tessa! Hold on!
- 我的天哪 - 我来了
- Oh, my God! - I'm coming!
坚持住
Hold on!
泰莎
Tessa!
太棒了 大黄蜂 你真棒
You're the best, Bee! You are the best.
没错 请永远不要忘记
You damn right! And don't ever forget it.
看着我 看着我 我们这不是下船了么
You see that? Look at me! We're off the ship, right?
大黄蜂 是自己人
Bumblebee! Bumblebee! Friendly!
敌船要逼近开火了 快上来 快上来
Enemy ships are coming in hot. Get on! Get on!
都坐稳了 人类
Hold your knickers, I'm punching it!
他们在追我们
They got three ships on them!
那我就再给点油
I'm giving it the juice!
大黄蜂 把他们干掉
Come on, Bee, take them out!
干得漂亮
Good move, Bee!
这是送给你的 混蛋
This one's for you, A-holes!
难道就没有更好的办法吗
If you're gonna do something, you better do it!
快
Come on!
我真是看不下去了 你掌舵 我来开火
I'm sick of this crap. You fly. I shoot.
嘿 你得先教我怎么开炮
Hey, you better let me fire this big-ass gun,
- 和这飞船怎么加速 - 哇 哇 哇
- And make this ship go faster! - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
我教你们速成 这是追踪枪
Listen up! Crash course. Tracer guns.
往前推是开火 往回扳是装弹
Punch forward to fire, slide back to reload.
什么
What?
推 顶 扳 重复 推 顶 扳 重复
Punch, hold, slide, repeat. Punch, hold, slide, repeat.
等等 你什么意思 一个没听懂
Wait. What're you talking about? I don't know what he means.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
你干嘛去
Where are you going?
和仇恨约会
To lay some hate.
- 重复 - 好
- Say it! - Okay.
推 顶 扳 重复 推 顶 扳 重复 上
Punch, hold, slide, repeat. Punch, hold, slide, repeat. Go!
耶 打中了一架
Yeah, I got one! Whoo!
这外星的枪太带劲了
These alien guns kick ass!
快点 要追上来了
Come on, he's on us!
大黄蜂 甩掉他 伙计
Bee, you gotta move! Duck!
大黄蜂 快开枪
Bee, fire the gun!
真刺激 泰莎 你没事吧
That was insane! Tess, you okay?
嗬 你牛哇
Okay. Sir?
你最好买了车险
You better have insurance!
车险
Insurance?
这是宇宙飞船 好吗
It's a freaking spaceship.
你有本事给它投保啊
You go get insurance on a freaking spaceship.
祝你好运 伙计
Good luck with that, buddy.
这是你的车吗
Is this your car? Huh?
宝贝 把我的外星枪拿过来
Sweetie, hand me my alien gun.
给你 老爸
Here you go.
下来
Come here.
相信老爸
Trust your dad.
好的
Okay.
为返回星际做好出发准备
Prepare for interstellar launch.
我们就要跟母船分离了
We're almost ready to separate. We're almost there.
快 飞船要返回了
Hurry, he's launching!
包在我身上
All over it, chief.
等"禁闭"回到宇宙深处
Lockdown will be in deep space,
他们才知道我已经跑了
Before he realizes I'm gone.
我的技术很烂 不过可以试试 走你
I'm a sucky pilot, but let's give it a whirl. Hell, yeah!
你们中情局可真是考虑周全 手法够利落
You CIA guys are really subtle. What a deft hand.
我相信没有人会察觉到
I'm sure nobody noticed all that.
听着 几分种后联邦调查员就会到
Look. In a few minutes, there are gonna be feds all over this place,
我不希望他们发现我们的成果
And I don't want them finding our Holy Grail.
我要把所有的研发机构
So we're gonna take all our R&D,
都转移到中国那边去
we're moving it to our China facility.
对 你还得把种子带给我
Yeah. I want you to bring me the Seed,
而且我需要你带到 那边去
But I want you to bring it to me there.
约书亚先生 在我看来
Mr. Joshua, I would not describe,
你的产品测试并不能被称作为完美
Your product testing as perfected.
我们还有大把的时间可以改进 去中国吧
We have plenty of time for improvements in China.
先生 惊破天 它绝对能够成为一个
Sir, Galvatron. He was...
怪物 一个四不像
A fiasco. A farrago.
一个莫大的耻辱
An embarrassment.
而且它张嘴了 怎么回事
And he spoke. How did that happen?
你知道一个瑕疵代表什么吗
Do you know what a flaw is, Wembley?
一个瑕疵 本质上就是一个彻底的失败
A flaw? A flaw is a total failure.
我都控制不了我的产品原型
I did not have control over my prototype,
所以我想知道 这到底是为什么
And I want to know why!
赶紧告诉大黄蜂好消息吧
Let's give Bumblebee the good news.
我们弄到船了 可以离开了
We got a ship now. We're leaving.
你们人类啊 我们尽力帮助你们
You humans. After all we have done.
你们居然还要自取灭亡
You don't know what you've wrought upon yourselves.
什么 你说什么 什么意思
What? What is it now? What are you talking about?
这已经超出我的能力范围了
I mean, I'm doing stuff out of my league here!
你们都不知道是谁在控制谁
You don't see who's controlling who.
我在和那个人造金刚战斗时
Within that manmade prototype I fought,
我感受到他存在的气场
I sensed the presence,
他就是威震天
Of Megatron.
发动芝加哥之战的那个霸天虎
What, the Decepticon that started the Chicago war?
不然你以为KSI是怎么做机器人的
How do you think KSI built those bots in the first place, hmm?
他们拿走了一堆死去的霸天虎的脑袋
They had a whole mess of dead Decepticon heads,
他们在下载他们的大脑内容
And they were downloading their minds!
而我是负责尸检工作
And I was in charge of autopsy duty.
没有工会撑腰 没有福利 什么都没有
No union, no benefits, no nothing.
他们把我连接到威震天
They hooked me up to Megatron,
他的大脑实际上没完全死亡
And that mind wasn't as dead as they thought.
他提供给他们技术和详细指标
He fed them the science and specs!
这样就能给他再造一个全新的身体
All so they could build him a brand-new body.
然后威震天用他那邪恶肮脏的虱子
Then he infected it with his evil,
传播他的染色体
Nasty chromosomes.
那些红眼珠子的小东西呀
They had red, beady eyes.
它们都寄居到我秀发里了
They got all in my lovely locks. Oh, I can smell it right now.
我现在还能闻到这个味道
Total inside custom job!
KSI给它起了个响亮的名字叫做惊破天
KSI might have named the body the snappy name of Galvatron,
但它只不过是威震天的化身而已
But that's just Megatron reincarnated!
你既然知道为什么不警告他们
You knew this and you didn't warn them?
小姑娘
Little girl,
你都想像不到那个死囚牢会有多黑暗
You can go to a pretty dark place when you on death row.
威震天一直把KSI玩弄于股掌之间
He's been playing KSI all this time,
这祥就好操纵他们帮他寻找种子
All so that he could manipulate them into going after the Seed.
等等 什么种子
Wait. The Seed?
我看见那些追杀我们的士兵
Those nasty soldiers that were chasing us.
他们上船时
I saw them board the ship,
带走了叫种子的东西
And they took something that they called the Seed.
那大约是六千万年以前的事情了
Listen. Sixty million years ago, give or take an eon...
数千颗行星被种子改造实现"赛博坦"化
Thousands of planets were cyber-formed with Seeds.
将你们这样的有机生命
They turned your organic life,
转为构成我们的基本金属元素
Into our elemental metals.
我们的造物主摧毁了你们的世界
Our creators destroyed your world,
才造就了我们
To make us.
那惊破天就是想再一次毀灭你们
And that's what Galvatron wants to happen again.
他想引爆那颗祌子 摧毀一座大都市
He wants to detonate that Seed in the biggest city,
并杀害数百万人
And kill millions!
他要对世界说 宝贝 我又回来了
He's gonna show the world, "Baby, I'm back."
爆炸的冲击波会将整座城市焚毁
The blast wave will incinerate that city,
融化成金属岩浆
Into molten metal.
他会组建一支庞大的军队
He'll have enough to build a massive army
并且会彻底灭绝你们人类
And annihilate your species forever.
你们这些贪婪的蠹货真是自掘坟墓
You dumb, greedy bastards just brought extinction to yourself.
但这不管我的事 我最终自由了
Not my problem, though. I'm free at last.
对我来说结局是好的 我老了
Whole thing worked out good for me. I'm walking.
必须要抢在惊破天之前取得种子
We got to get the Seed before Galvatron does.
(中国 北京)
那颗种子将是拯救我们公司的关键
The Seed is going to be the salvation of our company.
今晚就会运送过来 而下一个月
We take delivery tonight. And next month,
我们会在蒙古的沙漠安全引爆它
We detonate safely in the Mongolian desert.
然后创造出变形元素
And we'll create enough Transformium,
够用一百年的
For a hundred years.
(未经授权 严禁进入)
爸 我不想再逃跑了 也不想再偷东西了
Dad, I'm tired of running and stealing.
有地方睡觉了
Well, a place to sleep.
没错 还不用交房租
Yeah. Just another break-in.
我在你这个年纪的时候
You know, when I was your age,
有时候挺野的 喜欢飙车 泡妞
I liked to get a little wild. I liked cars, girls.
然后有了泰莎
But then there was Tessa.
她出生的时候
And when she was born,
我只求她能够平安健康和开心
All I ever wanted out of life was for her to be happy and healthy and safe.
我一直以为自己有能力保护她
Somehow I thought I'd always be enough to protect her.
以后不行了
But I won't be.
永远都不行
I'll never be.
但愿有人能做得更好
So somebody better be.
谢谢你能跟我们共患难
Thanks for being here today, Lucky Charms.
我也谢谢你没有趁机宰了我
Well, thanks for not shooting me when you had the chance.
以后有的是机会
Oh, I'll have more.
对 我想也是
Yeah, I can see that.
我们栏截到了加密的通讯信号
We've intercepted the encrypted communications.
约书亚·乔伊斯
Joshua Joyce,
正前住他位于中国广州的工厂
Is headed to his factory in Guangzhou, China.
嘿 大老板
Hey, big shot.
你的公司看起来麻烦不小
Your company's in serious trouble.
你最好请个好点的律师
You better have a damn good lawyer.
是吗 留给你自己吧
Really? Well, you better have a great one,
因为你要对毁灭整个城市负责
'Cause you're about to be responsible for the annihilation of a city.
你给我听好了
Now, you listen to me.
你的技术被黑了 你的产品原型被感染了
Your tech has been hacked. Your prototypes are infected.
而惊破天的目的是得到那个种子
And now Galvatron is after that Seed.
我知道你还有良心 因为你我都是发明家
Look. I know you have a conscience because you're an inventor, like me.
千万别给惊破天任何接近种子的机会
Do not let Galvatron anywhere near that Seed.
我在控制惊破天 它是我创造的
I control Galvatron. I created him.
我知道你心底很清楚
Deep down, I know you know.
是你的产品在控制你
Your prototype's been controlling you.
坐这个东西到地球的另一端有多快
How fast can that thing get us halfway around the world?
非常快 那可是宇宙飞船
Very. It's a spaceship.
我们如果要走 就现在走
If we're traveling, now's the time.
我只想生活回到从前 该怎么办你来定
All I want is to have our life back. It's your call. Whatever you want.
靠自己还是靠他们更安全呢
Are we safer on our own, or are we safer with them?
她能撑起个家
She's a keeper.
估计是随她妈妈
Must take after her mom.
这一点我无话可说
I can't argue with that, kid.
出发吧 我们要夺回种子
Move! We're retrieving the Seed,
这样守护人类的工作就了结了
But then we're done defending the humans.
什么 了结 你说了结什么意思
What, done? What do you mean, you're done?
意思就是结束了 再见 再会
Means "finished," "see ya," "good-bye."
他劫持了我飞船的一部分
Hijacked part of my ship?
你竟然让这种事发生
How did you let this happen?
关掉暗物质引摯
Shut down dark-matter drive,
光速倒车返回地球
Reverse course at light speed, and get us back!
撃天柱夺走了我的战利品展柜
Prime's taken my trophy case.
那就让他尝尝我的厉害
And he will feel my wrath!
(KSI中国厂区)
欢迎来到中国
Welcome to China.
把惊破天隔离好告诉工程师千万别激活他
Put Galvatron in containment. Tell the techs do not activate him.
您尽管放心吧
Absolutely, sir.
给我最高戒备
I want security on high alert.
乔伊斯
Joyce.
你不知道我多么迫不及待想把种子带给你
I cannot tell you how enthused I am to deliver this.
这是你最想要的外星科技
Top of your alien wish list.
它是你的了 或者说是 我们的了
It's yours. Or rather ours.
我想看看我的预付款
I will need to see my advance.
还有我那五百万份公司股权
Five million shares of the company.
我们将是人类战争的终结者
Together, we're gonna end human warfare.
我们将构建一个自动化的美军
We're about to build a fully automated U.S. Army.
多少美国人的性命将被挽救
Just think of all the American lives we're gonna save.
把惊破天运往隔离室
怎么样
All of,
这个车子很漂亮吧
These cars are KSI's,
这是我们KSI最好的跑车
Newest civilian prototype robots.
什么时候开始批量生产
So how soon until we can start continuous production?
要不我们先喘口气 这事呆会再说
You know, why don't we take a beat on this for a minute?
我这有新数据 是我刚发现的
I have some new data that I discovered and...
想打退堂鼓吗
You're not backing out on me here?
没有 我不想打退堂鼓
No, I'm not backing out. I just...
我是说我要种子 我没说我不要
I want the Seed. I'm not saying I don't want the Seed.
我只是说我不确定
I'm just saying I don't know if I...
是不是现在就需要 种子
If I want the Seed right now.
我的得力干将 为了种子送了命
Good men have died trying to get that thing,
这是为了我们 更是为了你
For us. For you.
我知道你为此干了什么
I know what you did to get that thing.
一连串令人作呕的非法勾当
A lot of illegal, icky shit.
我都能扳倒你 黑色行动 先生
I can take you down, too, Mr. Black Ops.
你休想威胁我
Don't you threaten me.
我年轻的时候创立了这家公司
I started this company when I was a boy,
而我的梦想是让世界変得更好
With a dream of making the world a better place.
有意思 我也有过同样的梦
Funny. I had the same dream.
但你不知不觉当中 却挣了几十亿美元
Somewhere along the way, you made billions of dollars.
那你说说我的梦缺了什么
So why don't you tell me what's missing from my dream?
我年轻时的梦想到底缺了什么
Why don't you tell me what's missing from my boyhood dream?
我为我的国家效力了几十年
I have served my country,
为实现无比繁荣竭尽全力
For decades of unparalleled prosperity
而你呢 就是我的黄金降落伞
And you are my golden parachute.
你要是识相的话
So you are damn well,
最好跟我一起从"飞机"上跳下去
Jumping out of the plane with me!
我是惊破天
I am Galvatron!
我没办法控制惊破天了
- 他正在摧毁所有的东西 - 怎么搞的
出什么事了
What's going on?
你的惊破天突然间就启动了
Your Galvatron has gone active.
你究竟还有什么在瞒着我
What haven't you been telling me?
叫达茜来 叫一部车到楼下 别闹出动静
Find Darcy, and bring a car around downstairs. Quietly.
厂区有紧急情况 你必须离开这儿
We got a factory emergency. I have to get you out of here.
出什么事了
What the hell's going on?
带他们出去
Take them outside.
我们有约定 你拿到了你想要的
We had a deal. You got what you wanted.
我拿得到了它想要的
I got what "it" wanted.
今天我要你们获得自由
My brothers, today I grant you your freedom.
从现在起 你们全部都听命于我 惊破天
And from now on, you are commanded by me.
起来
Rise up!
去找我的种子
Go find my Seed!
所有人从最近的出口疏散
到最大的城市里去引爆种子
Detonate the Seed in the largest city.
听着公主 别在跟我抱怨了
Listen, princess. I don't wanna hear, "I told you so,"
情况地区比我想的要危急
But this is much more dangerous than I think.
快上车
Get in.
惊破天黑进了其它产品
Galvatron's hacked into the others.
什么
What?
- 约书亚 你必须控制场面 - 开车
- Joshua. You have to contain this! - Drive, drive!
狗娘养的
Son of a...
跟上 快 跟上跟上
Come on. Let's move, let's move, let's move!
我会在香港除掉他们
I know how to lose them in Hong Kong.
我那边有些得力的朋友 他们可以帮忙
I know a military garrison there that will help us.
跟中情局职业杀手叫板
Threatening a professional CIA killer.
那可真不是什么明智的选择
Possibly not my finest hour.
我想收回我的话
I'd like to have that one back.
职业杀手 我以为他们是你朋友
Killer? I thought they were your friends!
不是朋友 是生意伙伴
No. Not friends. Business.
他们给了我这颗炸弹
They gave me this bomb.
炸弹
Bomb?
袋子里面装的是炸弹
Is there a bomb in the bag?
没错 袋子里面是炸弹
Yes, there's a bomb in the bag.
该死
Shit.
你说你不再为人类而战
When you said you were done fighting for humans,
你是开玩笑的吧
You didn't mean that, did you?
我们还要牺牲多少同类
How many more of my kind must be sacrificed
才能弥补你们的错误
To atone for your mistakes?
你以为人类多伟大 人就这样
Well, what do you think being human means? That's what we do.
我们当然会犯错
We make mistakes.
但有时错误中也会诞生出一些美好的事物
And sometimes out of those mistakes come the most amazing things.
我当初修好你 是为了获得奖金
When I fixed you, it was for a reward.
仅此而已 很简单 为了钱
That was it. That was why. For money.
你看我就犯了一个错误
And it was me making a mistake.
但不这样也不会有今天
Without it, you wouldn't be here.
就算你对我们完全绝望
So even if you got no faith in us,
也请你跟我做一样的事
I'm asking you to do what I do.
要在垃圾中发现宝藏
I'm asking you to look at all the junk and see the treasure.
你要有信心 摯天柱
You gotta have faith, Prime,
相信我们的能量
In who we can be.
(中国 香港)
拿不到钱 真让我不爽
I'm seriously pissed we're not getting paid for this.
不过 我们可以杀了他
Well, at least we get to kill him.
他逃不了 我用卫星追踪他
They're not getting away if I still got him on satellite.
这个天才 还以为能甩掉中情局呀
Some genius. Thinks he can outrun the CIA.
- 约书亚 - 怎么啦
- Joshua? - Yes?
这炸弹威力有多大
How lethal is that bomb?
嗯 我查查
Uh, I don't know. Let me check.
我喜欢 这太棒了 哦 等一下
I love this! This is so good. Oh, hang on.
老大从香港发来短信
I'm getting a text from Il Duce in Hong Kong.
我要知道种子的爆炸范围有多大
"Need to know the Seed's estimated blast range."
啊
Duh.
我来引开他们 把那东西转移到安全地方
I'll do the diversion! Get that thing somewhere safe!
嘿嘿嘿 这车多少钱啊
- 干什么 买我车 - 买你车呀 给你钱啊
杀手要来了 赶快离开这
Killers are coming! Guys, we gotta go!
- 三万卖不卖 - 哇 你有没有搞错
杀手要来了
Guys, guys...
- 你闭嘴 闭嘴 - 好好 你们慢慢谈
- Shut up! Shut up! - All right! I'm sorry! All right.
- 三万你卖不卖呀 - 不卖
- 你有没有搞错啊 - 这点钱当然不卖啦
走吧 走了 走了
Okay, good? No, don't go! Wait!
喂喂 卖了卖了
好的 好的
Okay, he's in.
- 就这价格赔给你了 - 就说吧 歉的你
- 我要求加薪 你要给我加薪 - 行
- I need a raise! I want a raise. - All right, yes!
都依你 都依你
I'm sure whatever you want!
快 快点
Go, go, go!
噢 不
Oh, no!
死神追上来了 死神追上来了
Death is on our tail! Death is on our tail!
全都给我让开 全让开
Get out of the way, all of you! Get out of the way!
我的天哪
I don't want to die like this.
包围他们
Box them in.
快点 快点
Hurry, hurry! Come, come.
好的 好的
Okay, yes. I'll follow you anywhere. You're amazing!
我得把你送到楼顶上去
We're going to get you to the roof.
好 你去哪我去哪
Good, good.
快进去
Go!
和战术核弹一样 还大笑
LOL. That's funny.
这事竟然成真的了
I can't... This is really happening.
一个像我这样身价超过两百亿的大老板
A man, me, who is worth over 20 billion dollars is now
正在 正在被杀手追杀 还是中情局的
Being chased by CIA assassins. That's the truth.
而且我还目睹了机器人造反
And in the middle of a robot uprising.
而且我还抱着一颗高级级炸弹
And I'm carrying what is, in essence,
相当于战术核弹
A tactical nuke.
而且最棒的就是我几乎用不着倒时差了
And the great thing is I... I'm barely feeling any jetlag.
- 你适可而止吧 - 什么
- Just stop it! - What?
你必须藏在这幢楼的楼顶
You need to hide on the roof of this building.
我会帮你安排直升机离开这里
I'll get you a helicopter extraction.
好的
Okay.
我喜欢她
I like her.
她太有魅力了
I find her very attractive.
他一定在这附近
He's definitely around here.
快走 快走
Come on, come on.
找到辆摩托车
I got a bike!
过去看看
Check in there!
那就是我刚才说的中情局杀手
These are the CIA assassins I told you about.
- 伙计们 - 我们走吧
- Guys. - Let's go.
帅哥
Hello.
- 别动 - 好的
- Hey! - Okay.
- 捡起来 - 好的
- Pick it up. - All right. I'm gonna.
哇哦
Wow.
哇哦 谢谢你 哇哦 你怎么会
Wow. Wow, thank you. Wow! How did you...
警校练的 然后才念得商学院
Police training, prior to my MBA.
我爱你
I love you.
快去楼顶吧你
Get to the roof.
好的
All right, okay.
给我找到种子 它就在附近
Find my Seed. It's here!
这些原型都在追那颗炸弹
Those prototypes are after that bomb.
不...
No...
那上面是什么人啊
Who the hell's aboard that?
这不可能
Impossible.
哦 天哪 这是什么
有没有搞错
弟兄们 是那拨汽车人 把他们击落
Brothers, it's the Autobots! Shoot them down!
约书亚
Joshua!
嘿 秃头
Hey, Baldy!
嘿 是我
Hey, it's me! Hey!
快上来 我们走吧
Bring it over now! Let's go.
快点 跑起来 快点 来
Hurry up, run! Hurry! Come on!
快 快点
Let's go! Move it!
伙计们 把炸弹给我
Guys! Come on. Give it to me now!
看来我们有伴了
Looks like we might have company.
我们被击中了
We're hit! We're hit!
他们活下来就会告发我们 我们就全完了
They live, they talk, we're dead.
全都干掉
Kill them all.
乐意效劳
Pleasure.
我上面有十层楼
I count ten below!
你说只有一个原型受到感染
I thought you said you had one prototype get infected.
但他又控制了其他五十个
Now he's got operational control of my other 50.
跟我来
Come on.
爬上去 爬上去 包围他们
Climb, climb! Surround them.
灾难或许是我造成的
I may have started the apocalypse,
但是你把家人扯进来
But you brought your family.
这样当家长实在太不称职了
And that's, you know, terrible parenting.
你再说费话我就把炸弹拿走
Oh, I'm about one second away from knocking you out taking the bomb,
把你留在这
And just leaving you here.
太好了 那就拜托你了
Please, do me a favor.
回答 擎天柱 还活着吗
Optimus, Autobots, you alive?
- 接招 小鬼 - 快走
- Come on, bitch! - Come on!
撤退 撤退 我们受到夹击
Evac! Evac! We're getting flanked!
下面还有敌人
We got company below!
我的屁股卡住了 大黄蜂 干掉他们
My fat ass is stuck! Bee, take the shot!
- 快快 进电梯 进电梯 - 快点
- Into the elevator! Get in. - Okay. Come on.
蹲下
Get down, get down!
把门关上
Close the door! Close the door!
怎么搞的 门关不上
Won't go! It's not closing!
是超重了 你们去找大黄蜂
There's too much weight. Get back down to Bumblebee!
爸爸别去
Dad, no!
没事
Well!
你找我对吗
Hey! You want me!
中央电梯 中央电梯
Center elevator. Center elevator.
他不会有事的
He's gonna be okay.
有外星炸弹
Alien bomb!
外星炸弹过来了 快让开 让开
Alien bomb, coming through! Clear the way! Clear the...
嗨 你好 小朋友
Hi, kids.
女士们 劳驾 让我过去一下
Coming through, ladies! Excuse me!
不好意思 让我过去 让我过去好吗
Excuse me, ladies! Excuse me! Oh, my God!
我的天哪 他们怎么这么淡定
How do you say, "Get the fuck out of the way" in Chinese?
下面还有很长一段距离呢
That's a long way down.
你跟我开玩笑的吧
You've got to be kidding me.
不
No!
我的天哪
Come on.
你跑不了啦
I'm coming for you!
你不该藏匿那辆卡车
Never should have hidden that truck.
那你也不该追杀我的家人
You should have never came after my family.
算你倒霉 我们都有家人
Tough luck, Yeager. We all have family.
对 但我要活着见到他们
Yeah, but I'm gonna live to see mine.
要我捉拿的对象究竟在哪儿
Where is my escaped bounty?
汽车人都在这里
Autobots at this location.
擎天柱就在附近
Prime is close.
你想做什么尽管去做
Do whatever you have to do.
这正合我的意
I intend to.
- 达茜 - 约书亚
- Darcy! - Joshua!
有三个人从那边追过来了
We got three more coming in from that way!
泰莎人呢
Bee, where's Tessa?
爸爸
Dad!
沒事了
It's Okay!
我现在进退两难了 各位
We got a real dilemma here. Okay?
我辛苦创造的超级机器人
I created incredible robots.
到头来却跟那个汽车人胖子较起劲来
It's all designed to kick that fat Transformer's ass.
说句真心话 这种局面谁都不想要
So, really, this is a no-win situation.
必须了结它
It's over.
嘴真欠
That was mean.
嘿 我很抱谦 可你得面对冷酷的现实
Hey! I'm sorry if you can't handle the cold-hearted truth!
擎天柱 这些人类我该怎么办
Optimus, what are my orders with these humans?
我能先干掉那颗光头吗
Can I squish the bald guy?
他们正身处危难
They're in trouble.
可这不是我们的战争
Nah! This isn't our fight!
我当落水狗当够了 真够惨的
I'm done being an underdog. Underdogs suck!
就让人类自作自受吧
I say they get what they deserve.
你怎么想 擎天柱
What's the play, Prime?
我们应该壮大我们的队伍了
It's time for reinforcements.
承认我们的新骑士成员
Recognize one of your Knights.
传奇 他的确存在
The legend exists.
快跑啊 快走
Come on.
快快快 我们走
All right, come on! Come on, let's go!
快 大黄蜂
Bee, go!
快离开这 快离开这里
Come on, we got to move! Let's go, move!
泰莎 来这边
Where's Tessa? Tessa, get over here!
这边来
Come on. Get over here!
跟在我后面 我掩护你们
Stay behind me! I'm covering you!
我要是顶不住了 说明我挂了
If I stop covering you, it means I'm dead.
但那是不可能的
But that ain't gonna happen.
去死
Take that!
我可是威猛的机器人战士
I'm a wicked warrior robot!
见鬼
Goddamn!
快 快跑
Come on! We gotta move now!
快跑
Go, go!
街上的敌人越来越多
We got hostiles coming down the street!
快跑
Go!
大黄蜂 12点钟方向 火力掩护
Bee! Twelve o'clock! Cover fire!
我们被包围了
We're surrounded!
快快快跑 快走
Hustle, hustle, hustle!
有火箭弹快蹲下 蹲下
Rocket!
快跑 快快 趴下 趴下
Go, go, go! Get down!
这地方真适合藏身 一个大玻璃箱子
Oh, this is the perfect place to hide. A big glass box!
你生怕别人不知道我们在哪吗 见鬼
Nobody will ever find us here! That's...
你不是在跟我开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
各位传奇的战士们
Legendary warriors,
当初缔造我们的力量
The powers that created us,
现在却希望我们全部灭亡
Now want us all extinguished.
我们必须联合起来
We must join forces,
不然我们将永世为奴
Or else forever be their slaves.
今天你们将与我们并肩作战
So today you stand with us...
否则 你们就站到了我的对立面
Or you stand against me.
让擎天柱自己解决吧
We'll let Prime figure this one out.
完全赞同
Very wise.
打死我也不会跟他们结成同盟
There's no friggin' way I'm staying down here with them.
没门 没门
No way. No way.
只有团结在一起 我们才能生存下来
Only together can we survive!
跟我战斗吧
Let me lead you!
哦不 还以为他会变成一辆大车呢
Oh, no. I was expecting a giant car.
过来吧
Come here!
我会给你们自由
We're giving you freedom.
你要么保护我的家人
You defend my family,
要么就去死
Or die.
汽车人 我们要证明我们的实力
Autobots, we're going to prove who we are,
让他们颤抖吧
And why we're here!
你就是甘愿为他去死
Ugh, you just want to die for the guy.
这就是领袖魅力或者说是洗脑之类的
That's leadership. Or brainwashing, or something.
不 那就是擎天柱的魅力
No. That's Optimus Prime.
伙计们 我们一起出击
Autobots, we charge together!
汽车人 出发
Now, roll out!
我们被包围了 哪边都有夹击
We're getting boxed in! We're getting flanked everywhere!
快帮我打 全都打下来
Help me out here! Kill anything that moves!
快点 凯德 开枪
Come on, Cade, shoot!
来吧 混蛋们
Come and get some, you little bitch!
注意导弹
Incoming!
我竟然把性命交给你保管了
I can't believe I'm putting my life in your hands.
别客气 拿着枪 快点 你能行的
Here. Be my guest. Take the gun. Come on, you can lead.
不 我不拿枪 我不拿枪 你拿着吧
No, I don't want the gun.
那你就把嘴给闭上
Then stay under there and shut up!
好啊
All right. You're good with the gun. So you keep it.
我的枪和弹药快不够用了
Running out of guns and ammo.
快来受死吧
Come and get some!
你们全都去死
You're all gonna die!
看你往哪儿跑
Way to go, baby!
打得好 凯德
Good shooting, Cade!
我就像个跳芭蕾舞的女胖子
I'm like a fat ballerina,
招招都是豁出去的
Who takes scalps and slits throats!
大爷我送你最后一程
Got your fortune cookie!
走你吧 小子
Come here, you little punk.
快打开保险 我顶不住了
Pull the pin! I'm dying out here!
拿着它 接着 接着
Here! Take it. Take it!
帮助他
Little help! Little help!
它要炸了 要炸了 要炸了
It's live! It's live, it's live. Take it!
那你让我怎么样
What do you want me to do with it?
扔出去呀
Just throw it!
给我 给我
Give, give, give!
有个坏消息 凯德
Got some bad news, Cade.
我沒弹药了 彻底没辙了
I'm out of ammo and out of ideas.
加快速度 快
Faster! Go!
我要杀了你
I'll kill you!
给我上
Charge!
不 这不可能 他们这是要毀掉我的一切
No, impossible! They're ruining everything!
去死
Take that!
离我远点
Get off me.
起来啊 探长
Get up, Hound!
我不行了
I can't go on.
你必须继续战斗
But you gotta keep fighting!
我没力气了
Tank's empty, bro.
更多敌人扑上来了
There's more of 'em coming.
你不上我们都会死的 快去呀
If you don't get up and fight, we're going to die. Let's go!
发动攻击
Attack!
我是擎天柱
Optimus is here!
大黄蜂 跳
Bee, jump!
我痛恨蹩脚的抄袭
I hate cheap knockoffs.
干得漂亮
Awesome job!
- 你 - 谁
- You. - Who?
你啊
You.
- 你给我过来 - 为什么是我
- Step forward. - Wait. Why?
你的科技将要为你们人类的灭绝而负责
Your science will be responsible for humanity's extinction.
好吧 我知道
All right. I know that,
你对生物伦理议题带来的困境很敏感
You're sensitive to this whole bioethical dilemma.
或许只是让你承认
Maybe all he wants to hear you say is,
有些东西就不该被发明
That some things should never be invented.
我懂了
Okay.
我们会带你们出城
We'll lead you out of the city.
把种子安全的带到山上去
Get that Seed safely to the hills.
用这辆车
Use this car.
它差点吃了我
He almost ate me!
这车还能开 快上去
All right, we're good!
让我来开吧
Get out of that seat.
有我在你运气真好
And you're one lucky dad to have me.
好小子行啊你 好吧 你来开
Okay, Lucky Charms. You got that. You drive. Let's go.
你干嘛呢
What did you do?
我不知道 我不知道 反正问题不小
I don't know. I don't know, but it's an issue.
- 你碰哪儿了 - 它会爆炸吗
- Did you press a button? - Is it gonna blow up'?
我 我不知道.
I don't know.
它在哔哔叫 你肯定是碰到了什么啊
Your thing is beeping now, so you must have hit something.
- 它会爆炸吗 - 我不知道
- Is it gonna blow up? - I don't know!
炸弹哔哔叫一定是有问题
A bomb starts beeping, that might signal a problem, you think?
我只是说它在有规律的闪着光
I'm just saying that it's a steady blinking light,
有可能是倒计时 也有可能是
Which could be a timer of some kind.
它在提供位置信息
Unless it's signaling location.
向谁提供
To who?
怎么样了
我们得请求中央政府支援
We've got to call the central government for help!
我现在就去打
走啊 快点
擎天柱
Optimus Prime.
来吧 来我这里
Come to me.
我靠
(中国 北京)
部长 紧急事件
Defenser Minister... there's a crisis in Hong Kong!
我是国防部长
I'm the Defense Minister.
- 此次在香港发生的事件 - 是外星人...
中央政府一定会全力支援香港
The central government will protect Hong Kong at all costs.
战斗机已经起飞了
We have fighter jets on the way.
桥在那儿
There's the bridge.
- 哇 哇 哇 小心 - 我的天啊
- Wow, Wow, Wow, - My God
倒车 倒车 我们要没命了 倒车
Back it up! Back it up!
别挡住视线 我看不见了 看不见了
Move! Get out of the way. I can't see!
好的 都冷静
Okay, just calm down.
肖恩 小心
Shane, watch out!
开快点
Whoa!
我来掩护
Get cover!
倒车 快倒车
Back up! Back! Back up!
汽车人 撤退
Autobots, fall back!
- 别挡路 让开 - 都让开
- Come on, move! Out of my way! - Get out of the way!
算了 撞就撞了
Just hit them! Just hit them!
那是什么呀
It's a big magnet!
它把金属吸上去又扔下来
It's sucking up metal and dropping it!
看着车 看着车
Look out! Look out!
- 肖恩 快点 快点 - 闪开 快闪开
- Go faster! Go faster! - Move!
它过来了 它越来越近了
It's coming! It's coming! It's coming closer!
开快点 肖恩
Go faster, Shane!
快让开 别挡道
Get out of the way!
小心...
Watch out...
又绕回我们这边了
Oh, no, now it's circling back towards us!
向右转 向右转
Hard right! Take a hard right!
快啊 肖恩 快
Move it! Get out of the way!
天啊
Oh, my God!
怎么了
Oh, no.
是大磁铁 下车 快下车
No, the magnet. Get out, get out!
大磁铁来了 快快快下车
Come on! Come here! Get out!
不...我被吸上去了
No, no, no! No, we're going up.
帮帮我拿炸弹 快 快拿炸弹呐
Grab the bomb! Help me grab the bomb!
我解不开安全带
I can't get the seat belt off!
别愣着 帮帮我 帮帮我
Pull me down! Catch me!
拿炸弹 我飘上去了
I'm going up! I'm going up!
抓住我 抓住我
Get me! Grab me!
我要飘上去了
Pull me down! Pull me!
我解不开安全带 解不开安全带
I can't get the seat belt off! I can't get the belt off!
我卡住了 我卡住了
I'm stuck! I'm stuck!
抓紧炸弹 使劲拉
Hold the bomb! I can't hold on!
- 快拉 - 拉啊 我撑不住了
- Pull! - Guys, it's crushing me!
小心
Car!
走
Move!
肖恩
Shane!
我沒事 我沒事 我沒事
I'm good! I'm good. I'm good.
大黄蜂
Bumblebee!
走开 伙计们
Hey, you guys!
他往这边来了
Come on.
快走
Go!
躲到安全的地方
Go find someplace safe.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
快找掩护
Get cover!
凯德
Cade!
汽车人 把这个炸弹从那座桥带离这个城市
Autobots, get this bomb over the bridge and out of the city!
爸爸
Dad!
快跑
What? Come on.
给我吧 我把炸弹带走
I got it! I'm getting this bomb out of here!
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
我俩该做个了断了
It's you and me now!
擎天柱正在孤军奋战
Look, Optimus is out there all alone.
什么 你帮不了他
What? You can't help him.
我得帮 他是为我们回来的
I have to, Tess. He came back for us.
爸你别走 求你了
Dad, don't leave, please.
好吧 我会回来的好吗
Look, I'll find you, I'll get there, okay?
不 你会死的
Dad, no, you'll die!
听我说 宝贝 你跟着肖恩会没事的
You gotta stay with Shane. You're gonna be okay.
你答应我要爱她
You promise me you're gonna keep her safe,
呵护她一生一世
Rest of her life, until the end of time!
你快说啊
Promise me!
我答应您
I promise you.
你是爸爸最心爱的宝贝
You're the best thing I ever made, Tess.
在爸爸心中没什么比得了你 我爱你
All right, don't ever forget it, it was always you. I love you.
求你了
Please.
快上车 上吧
Get in the car, now.
爸爸
Dad!
擎天柱
Prime!
快给我停车
Stop the car!
听我说
You better listen.
你听我说
No, you listen.
我不会丢下我爸不管
I'm not leaving my dad.
好的 我们要守住这条线
All right, we're gonna hold the line,
然后封锁这座桥
Then block the bridge!
成为一条汉子需要有耐心
You see, it takes patience to make a man.
耐心注视 忠实守护者天下苍生
The patience to watch and wait, to protect all of us, quietly,
效忠上帝和国家 不求功名与认同
For God and country, without any recognition at all!
凯德
Cade!
外星人无所谓是好的还是坏的
There are no good aliens! Or bad aliens, Yeager.
只不是我们和他们
It's just us and them.
而你选择了他们
And you chose them.
随时奉陪
Anytime.
你宁愿拯救人类也不愿拯救自己是吗
You saved the human instead of saving yourself?
我们的脸都被你丟尽了
You bring shame upon us all.
她就沒听过我的话 从来没有
She never listens. Never.
按我的指令行动
I gave you an order!
快点给我离开
Get out of here, now!
上车 宝贝
Get in. Get in.
嘿说你呢 嘿
Hey, you! Hey!
凯德 快离开这 这是属于我的战斗
Cade, get out of here! This is my fight!
也是我的战斗
It's my fight,
而你们只有死路一条
And you're all gonna die!
快 快
Go! Go!
拜托 加油
Come on! Come on!
不
No!
外星人杀手去死吧
Yeah! Killer robot, my ass!
来吧
Come on.
快离开 你们快走啊
Get away, all of you!
快 泰莎 快 泰莎 加油啊 泰莎
Come on, Tess. Come on, Tess. Come on, Tess.
开车
Drive!
看到我的脸你就死定了
You see my face, your life is done!
快点快点快点
Come on, come on, come on!
耶
Yeah!
光荣就在此刻
Honor to the end.
不后悔认识我吧
You still happy we met?
永不后悔
Always.
一切都结束
It's all over!
到这边来
Hurry!
快点 我要给禁闭设置炸弹 抓紧了
Quickly! I'm setting off Lockdown's grenade! Hold tight!
我们一定会再见面的 擎天柱
We shall meet again, Prime,
我已经重生了
For I am reborn.
偶尔做你的英雄也不错
Kind of nice being your hero for a change.
你永远都是 永远都是
You always were. All my life.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
回家参加毕业典礼吧
Let's go home to graduation, huh?
嗯 好
Yeah.
行啊 你小子
You're okay, kid.
你可真不赖 真不赖
Come here, you're all right. You're all right.
我们无家可归了 它被炸了
We don't have a home, Dad. It blew up.
也许我能帮上点忙
I might be able to help you with that.
勇敢的机器恐龙
Brave warriors...
你们自由了
You are free!
有空再去兜风啊 铁渣
I'll ride with you anytime, Spike!
你想我了吗
Did you miss me?
你说呢
No.
这颗种子属于我们的造物主
This Seed belongs to our creators,
虽然他们的身份尚未知晓
Whoever they are.
仍然有人在悬赏我这颗脑袋
There remains a price on my head.
我若留下来会连累你们大家
I endanger you all if I stay.
我会把这颗种子带到没人能找到的地方
I shall take it where it can never be found.
我们还会再见面吗
Will we ever see you again?
凯德·伊格
Cade Yeager,
我真的不知道
I do not know.
但当你抬头仰望星辰
But whenever you look to the stars,
请把其中的一颗星星
Think of one of them,
想成我的灵魂
As my soul.
请守护这一家人 汽车人
Defend this family, Autobots,
就如同他们守护你们一样
As they have you.
请守护他们
Defend
守护他们的未来
All they can be.
宇宙中有许多谜团是我们永远无法解开的
There are mysteries to the universe we were never meant to solve.
但我们的身份以及我们存在的原因
But who we are and why we are here,
并非无法解答
Are not among them.
这些答案就在我们的躯体之中
Those answers we carry inside.
我是擎天柱
I am Optimus Prime,
我要向我的造物主们发出一条信息
And this message is to my creators:
别找地球麻烦
Leave planet Earth alone.
否则我一定
'Cause I'm coming,
不会放过你们
For you.